<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Senthil Kumaran's thoughts.</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/</link><description>Senthil Kumaran's thoughts.</description><atom:link href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 17:59:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Masako Wakamiya, app developer of Hinadan</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/05/28/masako-wakamiya-app-developer.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interesting to watch this interview of 82 year old App Developer. She developed the app called &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hinadan/id1199778491?mt=8"&gt;Hinadan&lt;/a&gt; for people like her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="youtube-video"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="425" height="344" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dlhcybooMas?rel=0&amp;amp;hd=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is her story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wakamiya asked software developers to step in to develop her app. Uninterested, they suggested she make a game
herself. She took them up on the suggestion. Wakamiya soon bought programming books and
learned Apple’s Swift programming language through lessons with a programmer, nearly 200
miles away from her home in Japan's Kanagawa Prefecture, via Facebook Messenger and Skype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t the first time that Wakamiya took on a challenge.
She’s been dabbling in the tech field since the age of 60.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon retiring from a 43-year career as a bank clerk (she began at age 18), Wakamiya spent long hours caregiving
for her then-90-year-old mother. Feeling isolated, and seeking connection with the outside world, Wakamiya
bought her first computer, then moved on to a Microsoft PC, and later a Mac and iPhones. In between learning
the piano, at age 75, Wakamiya eventually joined a computer club for seniors, Mellow Club, learning to
create Excel art along the way. Then, this past year came Wakamiya’s focus on creating the game Hinadan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app, based on the annual Japanese doll festival of Hina Matsuri, invites players to arrange
12 ornamental dolls — representing the country’s emperor, family and guests — in a specific
order. The game requires in-depth memorization of various arrangements, and has become especially
popular with older women, who enjoy playing it with their grandchildren, Wakamiya said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.aarp.org/work/working-at-50-plus/info-2018/worlds-oldest-app-developer-fd.html"&gt;https://www.aarp.org/work/working-at-50-plus/info-2018/worlds-oldest-app-developer-fd.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/05/28/masako-wakamiya-app-developer.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 17:44:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: Guns, Germs and Steel</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/05/04/book-review-guns-germs-and-steel.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is hard for me write a review for as a great a book as "Guns, Germs and Steel". I had not read anything like that
before. It just opened me up to a whole new level of experience, and new set of expectations from books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think, I picked it up after reading Bill Gates review about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Like a lot of people, I was blown away by Diamond's Guns, Germs and Steel. I had never read anything that explained
so much about human history." - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gatesnotes.com/Books/Guns-Germs-and-Steel"&gt;Bill Gates, On Guns, Germs and Steel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made copious notes while reading this book, I wanted to preserve it for my future reference. I looked up many
different incidents in Wikipedia while reading this book. Every moment I spent was totally worth it. It will give a
reader a whole new understanding of the world. This book feels like a Magnum Opus, an experience provided to the reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first captive thing presented to me in this book was &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Cajamarca"&gt;The Battle of Cajamarca&lt;/a&gt; which lead to the fall of
the Inca Empire in South American Continent in 1500s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some data on this Battle. The left hand side is Spanish, and the right side is Inca Empire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/u2l3qvbh759cnbk/Screenshot%202018-05-04%2002.03.12.png?dl=0" class="align-center" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/u2l3qvbh759cnbk/Screenshot%202018-05-04%2002.03.12.png?dl=0" style="width: 350px; height: 200px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn't that startling? What happened? The reader is taken through the reasons for such decisive victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it steps back and goes the reason for why some developments took place at the places it took place. This
flow-chart from the book conveys the reason in a comprehensive way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/jo2c7hd29t9pg58/Screenshot%202018-05-04%2002.09.32.png?dl=0" class="align-center" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/jo2c7hd29t9pg58/Screenshot%202018-05-04%2002.09.32.png?dl=0" style="width: 450px; height: 600px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, a chapter on writing gives a whole history of human writing system. Which itself is fascinating, and the next
chapter was titled "Necessity's Mother".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an interesting twist on the commonly known proverb, "Necessity is the mother of all inventions". It just
asks, who was "Necessity's Mother". The answer is simple, it is the idle brain, curiosity. The chapter gives so many
details on the inventions that really took the world. I briefly wrote about it in this post &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/04/16/edison-and-his-phonograph.html"&gt;Edison and his phonograph&lt;/a&gt;
when I was reading that chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it deals with the idea of how the concept society and a religion must have formed. In the final chapters, it
goes into the fascinating story of China and Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is one thing about China that amazed me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/u8uejsmqffg7pol/Screenshot%202018-05-04%2002.20.09.png?dl=0" class="align-center" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/u8uejsmqffg7pol/Screenshot%202018-05-04%2002.20.09.png?dl=0"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about it, &lt;strong&gt;China sent huge ships with lots of people to expeditions way before Columbus set his foot on America!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the chapter on Africa, tells about the diversity of Africa, mentions about 1500 languages that originated in Africa.
And shares something that is very interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/wpd57lbf26fxo3t/Screenshot%202018-05-04%2002.22.02.png?dl=0" class="align-center" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/wpd57lbf26fxo3t/Screenshot%202018-05-04%2002.22.02.png?dl=0"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This just says two of modern religions of the world originated by the speakers of an African language.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is an answer from Jared Diamond to his friend from Papau New Guinea, on why westerners were more advanced
than his tribe. &lt;strong&gt;It does a great job of giving that answer to Mr. Yali and rest of us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/05/04/book-review-guns-germs-and-steel.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 08:53:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kotlin has a Javascript backend.</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/04/16/kotlin-has-a-javascript-backend.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I saw this tip in the IntelliJ, I was pleasantly surprised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/uljj8f71wfzsg1a/Screenshot%202018-04-16%2022.43.48.png?dl=0" class="align-center" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/uljj8f71wfzsg1a/Screenshot%202018-04-16%2022.43.48.png?dl=0"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://kotlinlang.org/"&gt;https://kotlinlang.org/&lt;/a&gt; might be an interesting one to get started on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another language, that is more close the metal, that I feel I should invest my time is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.rust-lang.org/en-US/"&gt;https://www.rust-lang.org/en-US/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/04/16/kotlin-has-a-javascript-backend.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 05:43:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Edison and his phonograph</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/04/16/edison-and-his-phonograph.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edison had invented &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phonograph"&gt;phonograph&lt;/a&gt;, a precursor to modern day music player and phone, but he not could get the proper
utility value of his invention immediately. I came across this paragraph in a book called, "Guns, Germs and Steel"
and felt compelled to note it down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/gnzzpjc9n82nfwp/Screenshot%202018-04-16%2013.57.59.png?dl=0" class="align-center" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/gnzzpjc9n82nfwp/Screenshot%202018-04-16%2013.57.59.png?dl=0" style="width: 450px; height: 300px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/04/16/edison-and-his-phonograph.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 21:17:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review - Manga Guide to Linear Algebra</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/04/07/book-review-manga-guide-to-linear-algebra.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13227038-the-manga-guide-to-linear-algebra" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="The Manga Guide to Linear Algebra" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1344690423m/13227038.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13227038-the-manga-guide-to-linear-algebra"&gt;The Manga Guide to Linear Algebra&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/653728.Shin_Takahashi"&gt;Shin Takahashi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2353816790"&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Manga Guide to Linear Algebra is a manga comic that teaches linear algebra concept. When I stumbled upon the terms Eigenvalues and Eigenvectors, I found those were greek to me, and I had no intuitive understanding of those terms. I decided to spend 4-hours to read about the basics of linear algebra from this book.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The book starts with the concept of sets, functions, and relations. Then introduces matrices, and then vectors. It gives a gentle introduction to various matrix operations. Gives visual clue on vector representations. Introduces the concept of linear dependence and linear independence in vectors.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Shows the examples of linear transformations which are practical applications of linear algebra and finally goes to introduce eigenvalues and eigenvectors. Finally, for Eigenvalues and Eigenvectors, these are the examples that are shown.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a example of 2x2 matrix for illustrating Eigenvectors given in the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
c_1[3, 1] + c_2[1, 2] [[8 -3]     -&amp;gt; c1[21, 7] + c_2[2, 4]
                       [2  1]]

c_1[3, 1] + c_2[1, 2] -&amp;gt; f[[8 -3]    -&amp;gt; c_1[7 [3, 1]] + c_2[2 [1, 2]]
                           [2  1]]
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image of the expression using the linear transformation, expressed using the same original vectors, but with
coefficients, 7 and 2 now. Then gives the example of 3 dimentional vector, and finally explains the the concept of
Eigenvalue and Eigenvectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the above example, 7 and 2 are eigenvalues, and (3, 1) and (1, 2) are the eigenvectors associated with those eigen
values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word &lt;cite&gt;eigen&lt;/cite&gt; seems to have come from german which means proper or characteristic.  It seems that we express the
original expression with the linear transformation properly using some values and vectors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/04/07/book-review-manga-guide-to-linear-algebra.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 19:24:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Coursera - Image and Video Processing: From Mars to Hollywood with a Stop at the Hospital</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/03/17/finished-coursera-course-image-and-video-processing-from-mars-to-hollywood-with-a-stop-at-the-hospital.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/image-processing/home/welcome"&gt;Image and Video Processing - From Mars to Hollywood with a Stop at the Hospital&lt;/a&gt; is the course offered
by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guillermo_Sapiro"&gt;Guillermo Sapiro&lt;/a&gt; at Coursera. After a long time, I voluntarily took a course and finished it. I didn't pay for
the course and so, I won't get a certificate. But I have this, and the course completion recorded in my
accomplishments in coursera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was wonderful course, I learnt about digital signal processing, and image transformations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/l1so7biomversfi/Image-Processing.png?dl=0" class="align-center" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/l1so7biomversfi/Image-Processing.png?dl=0" style="width: 450px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/03/17/finished-coursera-course-image-and-video-processing-from-mars-to-hollywood-with-a-stop-at-the-hospital.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 22:40:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Shelling Out - Origins of Money</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/03/06/shelling-out-origins-of-money.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I read this paper titled &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://fermatslibrary.com/s/shelling-out-the-origins-of-money"&gt;Shelling Out. The Origins of Money&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nick_Szabo"&gt;Nick Szabo&lt;/a&gt;
It starts with the origin of money in the european colony of the americas, how and
why a mass scale currency was introduced by colonists upon the native americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on this anecdote, it discusses some of the important properties of money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It defines the role of money to a basic human need for co-operation. Money, it says is delayed exchange of altruism
on part by humans. And money sould have properties like non-stealable, non-reproducible in order to be valuable. The
human society devised multiple tools for this kind. When the problem was met with scale, they invented a "fiat
currency", started in China, was way to scale currency, and keep a ledger for supply and demand.
The coin system that was first invented in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.ancient.eu/lydia/"&gt;Lydia&lt;/a&gt; is the same coin system that we use today, and the fiat currency
is still in use. Except now that we have the technology to scale currency without trusting or depending on a
government to maintain a ledger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>economics</category><category>paper</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/03/06/shelling-out-origins-of-money.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 17:33:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Odds</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/03/04/odds.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recollected this favorite poem of my mine from school days. I first read it in a Sportstar magazine and I don't
know the author of this poem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/q56odzlv987nu8u/Screenshot%202018-03-04%2011.46.21.png?dl=0" class="align-center" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/q56odzlv987nu8u/Screenshot%202018-03-04%2011.46.21.png?dl=0"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>poem</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/03/04/odds.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 19:35:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Image Filters - Sobel, Laplacian, Canny</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/02/24/image-filters-sobel-laplacian-canny.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was trying to understanding the various egde detectors we can use in Open CV. Trials done were following the
examples in the book OpenCV with Python by Example by Prateek Joshi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/ha9ttqytpvj8f6t/Screenshot%202018-02-24%2018.46.52.png?dl=0" class="align-center" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/ha9ttqytpvj8f6t/Screenshot%202018-02-24%2018.46.52.png?dl=0" style="width: 650px; height: 400px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/02/24/image-filters-sobel-laplacian-canny.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 03:10:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Radians and Roger Coats</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/02/17/radians-and-roger-coats.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When trying to understand the concept of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radian#History"&gt;radians&lt;/a&gt;, I came across the inventor of the concept &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roger_Cotes"&gt;Roger Coats&lt;/a&gt;
His name is not familiar to many. I understood, he is known for working closely with Isaac Newton by proofreading the
second edition of his famous book, the Principia, before publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cotes died from a violent fever in Cambridge in 1716 at the early age of 33. Isaac Newton remarked, "If he had lived we would have known something."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>maths</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/02/17/radians-and-roger-coats.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 21:23:54 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>