<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Senthil Kumaran</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/</link><description>Senthil Kumaran</description><atom:link href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 11:58:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Being a polymath is natural</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/29/being-a-polymath-is-natural.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition admonition-being-a-polymath"&gt;
&lt;p class="first admonition-title"&gt;Being a polymath&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;Polymaths such as Da Vinci, Goethe and Benjamin Franklin were such high achievers that we might feel a bit reluctant
to use the word ‘polymath’ to describe our own humble attempts to become multi-talented. We can’t all be geniuses.
But we do all still indulge in polymathic activity; it’s part of what makes us human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://aeon.co/essays/we-live-in-a-one-track-world-but-anyone-can-become-a-polymath"&gt;Master of many trades&lt;/a&gt; By Robert Twigger&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/29/being-a-polymath-is-natural.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 22:30:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Folding@Home for COVID-19</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/28/started-folding.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I setup &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://foldingathome.org/"&gt;Folding@Home&lt;/a&gt; and started contributing computing resources to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://foldingathome.org/covid19/"&gt;Covid-19&lt;/a&gt; project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/s/h4n6u8p9uut8xzd/IMG_20200328_191444.jpg" src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/s/h4n6u8p9uut8xzd/IMG_20200328_191444.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stats: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://stats.foldingathome.org/donor/Senthil.Kumaran"&gt;https://stats.foldingathome.org/donor/Senthil.Kumaran&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="https://stats.foldingathome.org/donor/Senthil.Kumaran"&gt;&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/uab0psll81ufw2z/folding-at-home.png" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/uab0psll81ufw2z/folding-at-home.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:Folding@Home"&gt;Folding@Home&lt;/a&gt; hit a milestone Exaflop computing speed, which is a billion billion floating point operations per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let's not leave any stone unturned.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="resources"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation instructions for &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://foldingforum.org/viewtopic.php?f=16&amp;amp;t=31972#"&gt;Ubuntu 19.10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/26/coronavirus-pushes-foldinghomes-crowdsourced-molecular-science-to-exaflop-levels/"&gt;Coronavirus pushes Folding@Home’s crowdsourced molecular science to exaflop levels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/28/started-folding.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 02:19:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bill Gates Follow up Q/A on Covid-19</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/25/bill-gates-follow-up-qa-on-covid-19.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bill Gates followed up with a Live Question and Answer session with TED's Chris
Anderson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testing&lt;/strong&gt; is the still "key part".  We need a way to find to detect who
has-virus and who does not. This is done using swabs. &lt;em&gt;All of us, will have
to be tested before we resume social interaction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He is still very much concerned about developing countries, like India,
Pakistan, and countries in the southern hemisphere, as he perceives, will
have more difficulty than developed countries like the US to get this
through.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Economic Impact&lt;/em&gt; can be reversed, but if a life is lost, it cannot be
brought back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The idea of building herd-immunity against this virus, in reality,  doesn't
look like a choice. The numbers don't add up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please watch the entire video conversation here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/TED/videos/1071228706574778/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/TED/videos/1071228706574778/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/25/bill-gates-follow-up-qa-on-covid-19.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 13:38:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>On Mentors - Katherine Johnson and William Schieffelin Claytor</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/24/on-mentors-katherine-johnson-and-william-schieffelin-claytor.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I came to know today that Katherine Johnson had a excellent teacher, guide and a mentor in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Schieffelin_Claytor"&gt;William Schieffelin Claytor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.imgur.com/VNmVRsy.png" src="https://i.imgur.com/VNmVRsy.png"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/24/on-mentors-katherine-johnson-and-william-schieffelin-claytor.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 04:30:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bill Gates Q/A about COVID-19</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/20/gates-notes-qa-about-covid-19.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bill Gates did a Ask Me Anything on Covid-19 on Reddit. The entire AMA is educational, read it in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Coronavirus/comments/fksnbf/im_bill_gates_cochair_of_the_bill_melinda_gates/"&gt;reddit&lt;/a&gt; or in
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gatesnotes.com/Health/A-coronavirus-AMA"&gt;Gates Notes AMA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following question and answers caught my attention in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition admonition-bill-gates-ama-on-covid-19-some-question-and-answers"&gt;
&lt;p class="first admonition-title"&gt;Bill Gates AMA on Covid-19 - Some question and answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;What about the current crisis worries you the most? What gives you the
most hope?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill: &lt;em&gt;The current phase has a lot of the cases in rich countries.
With the right actions including the testing and social distancing (which I
call “shut down”) within 2-3 months the rich countries should have avoided high
levels of infection. I worry about all the economic damage but even worse will
be how this&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;will affect the developing countries&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;who cannot do the social
distancing the same way as rich countries and whose hospital capacity is much
lower.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;I read the&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/media/imperial-college/medicine/sph/ide/gida-fellowships/Imperial-College-COVID19-NPI-modelling-16-03-2020.pdf"&gt;Imperial College COVID-19 Response Team report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;as well as&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/jeremycyoung/status/1239975682643357696"&gt;this explanation in a historical context&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Essentially, it
says that by doing nothing, 4 million Americans die. Through the mitigation
strategy—i.e. social distancing and “flattening the curve”— it says that 1.1-2
million Americans will die. However, it also says that the suppression
strategy, or “shutting everything down for 18 months”—will lead to only a few
thousand people dying.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you agree with these numbers, and if so, is there any excuse for not
immediately issuing a shelter in place order for the entire country?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill: &lt;strong&gt;Fortunately it appears the parameters used in that model
were too negative.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The experience in China is the most critical data we
have. They did their “shut down” and were able to reduce the number of cases.
They are testing widely so they see rebounds immediately and so far there have
not been a lot. They avoided widespread infection. The Imperial model does not
match this experience. Models are only as good as the assumptions put into
them. People are working on models that match what we are seeing more closely
and they will become a key tool. A group called Institute for Disease Modeling
that I fund is one of the groups working with others on this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;How is the economy likely to recover after all of this
in your opinion?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill: &lt;em&gt;Yes eventually. The economic impact of the “shut down” will be
large but if it is done well (including the testing piece which I keep
mentioning) eventually we can open back up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;How is your foundation helping the current pandemic? Are you
donating money, producing products for health workers?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill: &lt;em&gt;Our foundation is working with all the groups who make
diagnostics, therapeutics and vaccines to make sure the right efforts are
prioritized. We want to make sure all countries get access to these tools. We
donated $100M in February for a variety of things and we will be doing more.
One priority is to make sure that there is enough manufacturing capacity for
therapeutics and vaccines.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;We have other efforts like our education group
working to make sure the online resources for students are as helpful as they
can be.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;Is there anything you can do to assist with ventilator production?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill: &lt;em&gt;There are a lot of efforts to do this. If we do social
distancing (“shut down”) properly then the surge of cases won’t be as
overwhelming.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Our foundation’s expertise is in diagnostics, therapeutics and
vaccines so we are not involved in the ventilator efforts but it could make a
contribution to have more especially as the disease gets into developing
countries including Africa.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;What do you see as the long-term strategy for fighting this
pandemic and do you feel like it will adequately prepare us for the next?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;Bill: &lt;em&gt;I think that after this is under control that Governments and
others will invest heavily in being ready for the next one. This will take
global cooperation particularly to help the developing countries who will be
hurt the most. A good example is the need to test therapeutics wherever the
disease is to help the whole world.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The Virus doesn't respect national
boundaries.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="related-resources"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Related Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gatesnotes.com/Health/We-Are-Not-Ready-for-the-Next-Epidemic"&gt;On preparing for next epidemic in 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/media/imperial-college/medicine/sph/ide/gida-fellowships/Imperial-College-COVID19-NPI-modelling-16-03-2020.pdf"&gt;Imperial College Covid-19 Response Team Report that led to Shut-down strategy in US&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/covid-19/home/welcome"&gt;Coursera - Science Matters - Let's Talk About COVID-19 by Imperial College London &amp;amp; J-IDEA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/20/gates-notes-qa-about-covid-19.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 20:13:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Discovery of Radium by Madame M. Curie</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/16/the-discovery-of-radium-by-madame-m-curie.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a short text available for reading in project gutenberg, titled &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gutenberg.org/files/61622/61622-h/61622-h.htm"&gt;"The Discovery of Radium by Marie Curie"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="https://www.gutenberg.org/files/61622/61622-h/61622-h.htm"&gt;&lt;img alt="https://www.gutenberg.org/files/61622/61622-h/images/cover.jpg" class="align-center" src="https://www.gutenberg.org/files/61622/61622-h/images/cover.jpg" style="width: 350px; height: 500px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some interesting quotes from this book&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition admonition-pursuit-of-truth"&gt;
&lt;p class="first admonition-title"&gt;pursuit of truth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Then I took up measurements of minerals and I found that several of those
which contain uranium or thorium or both were active. But then the activity
was not what I could expect, it was greater than for uranium or thorium
compounds like the oxides which are almost entirely composed of these
elements. Then I thought that there should be in the minerals some unknown
element having a much greater radioactivity than uranium or thorium. And I
wanted to find and to separate that element, and I settled to that work
with Professor Curie. We thought it would be done in several weeks or
months, but it was not so. It took many years of hard work to finish that
task. There was not one new element, there were several of them. But the
most important is radium which could be separated in a pure state.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition admonition-work-of-science"&gt;
&lt;p class="first admonition-title"&gt;work of science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;&lt;em&gt;But we must not forget that when radium was discovered no one knew that it
would prove useful in hospitals. The work was one of pure science. And this
is a proof that scientific 5 work must not be considered from the point of
view of the direct usefulness of it. It must be done for itself, for the
beauty of science, and then there is always the chance that a scientific
discovery may become like the radium a benefit for humanity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/16/the-discovery-of-radium-by-madame-m-curie.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 22:18:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Covid-19 Exponential Growth Lecture of 3Blue1Brown</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/15/covid-19-exponential-growth-lecture-of-3blue1brown.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;3Blue1Brown did an excellent video explaining exponential growth. He took the
opportunity to explain Covid-19, growth, trajectory and more importantly
pressing question on when this growth will stop using mathematical equations.
I was highly impressed. It helped to make sense of the situation, and help with
dealing with the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please watch this video&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="youtube-video"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Kas0tIxDvrg?rel=0&amp;amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allow="encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The video deals with the questions explained in the slide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.imgur.com/46Tu2D9.png" src="https://i.imgur.com/46Tu2D9.png" style="width: 550px; height: 350px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exponential growth means as you go from one day to the next, it involves
multiplying by a constant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.imgur.com/Rk3p1TP.png" src="https://i.imgur.com/Rk3p1TP.png" style="width: 550px; height: 350px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of an Equation the exponential growth is represented mathematically
like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.imgur.com/sTmqAyB.png" src="https://i.imgur.com/sTmqAyB.png" style="width: 550px; height: 350px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3Blue1Brown says that this data fits in a linear regression model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linear regression calculates an equation that minimizes the distance between
the fitted line and all of the data points.  And if want to find the equation
that minimizes the distance between a line and the data point, the most common
way is to find &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.mathsisfun.com/data/least-squares-regression.html"&gt;"least square regression"&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will notice that the least square regression ends up with an equation of
line &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(y = m \dot x + b\)&lt;/span&gt; Where &lt;cite&gt;m&lt;/cite&gt; is same as the multiplying factor the
exponential growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So he uses the data point to track the growth for linear regression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.imgur.com/K1FQ7E1.png" src="https://i.imgur.com/K1FQ7E1.png" style="width: 550px; height: 350px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finds out &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(R^2\)&lt;/span&gt; which is a coefficient of determination,  a
statistical measure of how close the data are to the fitted regression line.
We notice that &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(R^2\)&lt;/span&gt; is close to 1.0 which is a straight line, increasing
by a factor, &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(m\)&lt;/span&gt; each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is making a point with logistic regression that, when a country has 100
times lower cases than another country, the country is not 100 times better,
but just 30 days behind!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.imgur.com/BrhVPIU.png" src="https://i.imgur.com/BrhVPIU.png" style="width: 550px; height: 350px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And following the numbers, if we extrapolate, we will hit a 1 billion cases in
81 days. But that's hardly desirable, and everyone wants to know when we do
stop growing linearly and hit a plateau. He notes that "Linear Growth" is a
theoretical phenomenon, not a realistic one. Just like, if you were not married
last year, and you got married this yea, it does not mean, will you marry every
year from now. (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.explainxkcd.com/wiki/index.php/605:_Extrapolating"&gt;Explain XKCD&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.imgur.com/q0h9nux.png" src="https://i.imgur.com/q0h9nux.png" style="width: 550px; height: 350px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But unlike marriage, we &lt;strong&gt;are&lt;/strong&gt; seeing an exponential growth here. We will have
to find out the factors that reduce the exponential growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in reality what we are expecting is a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logistic_function"&gt;logistic curve&lt;/a&gt; where the
exponential growth includes damping factor contributed by people who are not
infected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our whole idea, then becomes to &lt;strong&gt;increase this damping factor&lt;/strong&gt;, that is not
get infected by this virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.imgur.com/vpRwguZ.png" src="https://i.imgur.com/vpRwguZ.png" style="width: 550px; height: 350px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What makes the growth factor go down other than maxing out at the total population?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.imgur.com/mAX2ICl.png" src="https://i.imgur.com/mAX2ICl.png" style="width: 550px; height: 350px;"&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decrease the number of people getting exposed - aka social distancing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decrease the probability of exposure - aka wash your hands completely, maintain hygiene amongst other things.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And important point to remember in this damping factor is, the &lt;strong&gt;output decreases exponentially too&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance with the growth factor of 1.15, we have the first number and
reduces significantly, only by &lt;em&gt;10%&lt;/em&gt; decrease in the damping factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.imgur.com/FltSCBb.png" src="https://i.imgur.com/FltSCBb.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.imgur.com/aka3Jxt.png" src="https://i.imgur.com/aka3Jxt.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3Blue1Brown has tried to quantify our worry factor, and give us hope that by
social distancing, good hygiene we can reduce the damping factor and control
the growth. However, "If we are not worried, that's only thing to worry about".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Articles / Simulations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2020/world/corona-simulator/"&gt;Why outbreaks like coronavirus spread exponentially, and how to flatten the curve by Harry Stevens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/15/covid-19-exponential-growth-lecture-of-3blue1brown.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 21:13:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Happy Pi Day</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/14/happy-pi-day.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div class="section" id="happy-pi-day"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Happy Pi Day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I celebrated the Pi day during Covid-19 times with these activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://noahgift.github.io/aws-ml-guide/lessons/Lesson4_AWSML_Modeling.html"&gt;AWS ML Modelling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solving an Easy Brilliant.org quiz but getting it wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.imgur.com/ZvUKjlw.png" src="https://i.imgur.com/ZvUKjlw.png"&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading a little about Thales Theorem  from the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://mathigon.org/timeline"&gt;Timeline of Mathematics&lt;/a&gt; at Mathigon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://i.imgur.com/xsLzOCV.png" src="https://i.imgur.com/xsLzOCV.png"&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also did a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://leetcode.com/contest/weekly-contest-180"&gt;leetcode weekly contest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/14/happy-pi-day.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 16:12:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: Blown to Bits</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/12/book-review-blown-to-bits.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3063035-blown-to-bits" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="Blown to Bits: Your Life, Liberty, and Happiness After the Digital Explosion" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1348371255l/3063035._SX98_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3063035-blown-to-bits"&gt;Blown to Bits: Your Life, Liberty, and Happiness After the Digital Explosion&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/1312233.Hal_Abelson"&gt;Hal Abelson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/3003927797"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Bits are Bit. Even if they are transmitted through electrons in copper wires or light in fiber optical cables or via modulation in radio waves. All of these carry bits and run the world. This book covers the intersection between technology, society, the justice system, policies, and politics. It is highly approachable and helps you appreciate technology, not just from a technical standpoint but from a societal standpoint. I really appreciate the concern for fellow human beings put forefront in this book. It opens the reader's mind to care a lot about the political process and be aware that any technology we design is going to have a wide societal impact.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;The entire book is available free online: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bitsbook.com/excerpts/"&gt;http://www.bitsbook.com/excerpts/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/03/12/book-review-blown-to-bits.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 16:29:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Interview with Vladimir Vapnik</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/02/28/interview-with-vladimir-vapnik.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="youtube-video"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bQa7hpUpMzM?rel=0&amp;amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allow="encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was an unbelievable interview with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vladimir_Vapnik"&gt;Vladimir Vapnik&lt;/a&gt;. He is the co-inventor of Support Vector Machines, one of
widely used statistical machine learning algorithm. In explaining his understanding of the world, he uses the
mathematical terms of predicate and functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He often went back to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://changingminds.org/disciplines/storytelling/plots/propp/31_narratemes.htm"&gt;Vladimir Propp&lt;/a&gt; to 31 functions that explained russian folk tales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vladmir Vapnik is a truly a humble, honest, accurate person, trying to &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; and then solve a well defined
problem of Hand-writing recognition, within his lifetime. I was amazed while listening to him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/02/28/interview-with-vladimir-vapnik.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 14:03:09 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>