<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Senthil Kumaran's thoughts. (Posts about books)</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/categories/books.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 05:30:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Book Review: They Called Us Enemy by George Takei</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2019/10/06/book-review-they-called-us-enemy-by-george-takei.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/42527866-they-called-us-enemy" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="They Called Us Enemy" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1541125895l/42527866._SX98_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/42527866-they-called-us-enemy"&gt;They Called Us Enemy&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/260482.George_Takei"&gt;George Takei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/3003892657"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This book is a straightforward narration by Georgia Takei of a Japanese Internment by the US Government during World War II. George and his family had suffered this cruelty. He highlights how opportunistic senators took chances to rise to power by promoting racial discrimination.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I had not known about this part of US history. I also did not know how ACLU helped the Japenese in the US then. US had detained 250,000 Japanese families living in the US, many of them US citizens, into camps during WWII.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Having lived through this horror, a lot of these Japanese families restarted and rebuilt their lives again. George Takei turned to activism to share his story with the masses, and I think he has been very effective.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This book has come the right time when similar mistreatment is being carried out by certain opportunistic politicians.&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2019/10/06/book-review-they-called-us-enemy-by-george-takei.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 05:29:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review - The Mahabharata: A Shortened Modern Prose Version of the Indian Epic</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2019/10/06/book-review-the-mahabharata-a-shortened-modern-prose-version-of-the-indian-epic.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20657408-the-mahabharata" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="The Mahabharata: A Shortened Modern Prose Version of the Indian Epic" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1391108802l/20657408._SX98_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20657408-the-mahabharata"&gt;The Mahabharata: A Shortened Modern Prose Version of the Indian Epic&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/1305302.R_K_Narayan"&gt;R.K. Narayan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/3003633849"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Mahabharata is one of the most complex stories I have ever read. I read this book following The Ramayana by R.K.Narayan. The ethical dilemmas presented in this story is at a whole different level than Ramayana. While in Ramayana, there are good guys and bad guys in Mahabharata there is nothing like that.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;No one is entirely good or no one is entirely bad. The Pandavas and Kauravas are brothers, just competing against each other, but their quarrel reaches to a level for war.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Coming to the war, which is an important topic of this story, the book has 3 chapters dedicated to the avoidance of war and only one chapter for the war.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In spite of suffering all the atrocities presented by Duryodhana, Pandavas realize that war is not good for anyone, and try for multiple attempts to prevent the war. Duryodhana plays politics and chooses to listen, and highlight points only which could give a chance for war.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And when it comes to war, Pandavas understands that a deterministic outcome is achieved by eliminating everyone in the enemy camp, even babies. So, after trying to avoid war, when the war becomes inevitable, Krisha proposes and leads a _genocide_ against the Kaurava clan.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To me, the most complex characters in this story were that of Karna and Krishna. &lt;br&gt;Karna has chances to prevent war, he understands his background well but still chooses to side with Duryodhana. Krishna is one who leads the Pandavas to war and gives guidance "on duties" in ambiguous times.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;There is no good or a bad person in this entire story.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2019/10/06/book-review-the-mahabharata-a-shortened-modern-prose-version-of-the-indian-epic.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 01:16:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: A Mind for Numbers by Barbara Oakley</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-a-mind-for-numbers-how-to-excel-at-math-and-science-even-if-you-flunked-algebra.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18693655-a-mind-for-numbers" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="A Mind for Numbers: How to Excel at Math and Science (Even If You Flunked Algebra)" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1387148777m/18693655.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18693655-a-mind-for-numbers"&gt;A Mind for Numbers: How to Excel at Math and Science&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/669905.Barbara_Oakley"&gt;Barbara Oakley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2535923139"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Like most readers, I stumbled upon this book after taking Barbara Oakley's Learning How to Learn Course in Coursera. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This book reinforces the concepts taught in that course. The idea of relaxed learning, giving ourselves plenty of time while learning difficult concepts, avoiding procrastination, and tools that help us avoid the procrastination. The idea of repetition for remembering different concepts is presented and stressed well this book.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The importance of sleep for learning stayed with me and changed me when I took the course based on this book. I never discount sleep for important exams or deadlines now.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The crux of learning is expressed well by this quote from Santiago Ramón y Cajal introduced to us in this book&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br&gt;What a wonderful stimulant it would be for the beginner if his instructor, instead of amazing and dismaying him with the sublimity of great past achievements, would reveal instead the origin of each scientific discovery, the series of errors and missteps that preceded it - information that, from a human perspective, is essential to an accurate explanation of discovery. &lt;/i&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Santiago Ramón y Cajal&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-a-mind-for-numbers-how-to-excel-at-math-and-science-even-if-you-flunked-algebra.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 15:50:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review - The Ramayana By R.K. Narayan</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-the-ramayana-by-rk-narayan.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/129876.The_Ramayana" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="The Ramayana: A Shortened Modern Prose Version of the Indian Epic" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1309283297m/129876.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/129876.The_Ramayana"&gt;The Ramayana: A Shortened Modern Prose Version of the Indian Epic&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/1305302.R_K_Narayan"&gt;R.K. Narayan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2771509811"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is Narayan's narration of the famous Indian Epic, Ramayana. It follows Valmiki's script, instead of the Kamban, that I thought, I would expect from the South Indian author. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The introduction gives the details of the Ramanand Sagar's Television series and how India stood still when Ramayan was telecast on weekends. The story is well know, but the best part of this book are in the details.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I liked the chapter on Vali and Sugreeva, wherein the author does not mince words and shares about the ethical lapse of Rama. That was a difficult chapter in Ramayana. Rama tries to help Sugreeva to fight against his brother Vali. He kills Vali by hiding. Rama being a warrior, is supposed to fight straight, and being righteous person, who is supposed to not harm anyone unnecessarily, forgoes both in this episode. Vali questions him about this. And Rama rationalizes that Vali is not a sub-human, Monkey, but a higher form since he possesses the judgement skills of Right vs Wrong, and since Vali choose the Wrong approaches, when knowing what was Right, he had to meet with this fate. Also, by having killed by Rama, Vali is elevated to higher form in his death.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Other mistakes of Rama are explained as a consequence of Rama forgetting his inherent divinity, making mistakes as a human, and needed constant reminders from gods. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This book is action packed, has good stories, morals, stories of ethical dilemmas and is entertaining. The author does a very good job of maintaining balance of religious piety and story telling in this book. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-the-ramayana-by-rk-narayan.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 21:43:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review:  The Smart Girl's Guide to Privacy: Practical Tips for Staying Safe Online</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-the-smart-girls-guide-to-privacy-practical-tips-for-staying-safe-online.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25644910-the-smart-girl-s-guide-to-privacy" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="The Smart Girl's Guide to Privacy: Practical Tips for Staying Safe Online" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1433187260m/25644910.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25644910-the-smart-girl-s-guide-to-privacy"&gt;The Smart Girl's Guide to Privacy: Practical Tips for Staying Safe Online&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/50868.Violet_Blue"&gt;Violet Blue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2735463770"&gt;3 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is a checklist book for the various steps that a person can take to stay secure and manage their privacy online. This is written for general populace, and does a good work to highlights of perils of getting hacked online, problems associated with online privacy. Author provides references to tools and mechanisms that can help person stay safe online.&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-the-smart-girls-guide-to-privacy-practical-tips-for-staying-safe-online.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 17:01:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review - Autonomy: The Quest to Build the Driverless Car — And How It Will Reshape Our World</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-autonomy-the-quest-to-build-the-driverless-car-and-how-it-will-reshape-our-world.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autonomy: The Quest to Build the Driverless Car—And How It Will Reshape Our World by Lawrence D. Burns,  Christopher Shulgan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36039329-autonomy" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="Autonomy: The Quest to Build the Driverless Car—And How It Will Reshape Our World" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1531803242m/36039329.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36039329-autonomy"&gt;Autonomy: The Quest to Build the Driverless Car—And How It Will Reshape Our World&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3189685.Lawrence_D_Burns"&gt;Lawrence D. Burns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2652404433"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This book reminded me of "The Road Ahead" by Bill Gates. This is an impressive account on Self Driving Technology, that is about to come and consume us in the near future. The book is very well written. Initially, I had plenty of doubts on the author, Lawrence D Burn's style, thinking that he was one of the pure management type guys, looking at things in a disconnected way, trying to associate himself with changes brought about by others. I was proven wrong. I started appreciating his insights, his outlook towards this project, his commitments, and really understood where he was coming from when the author provided more context into his own up bringing and background. He provided the view from Detroit, that many following the self-driving space will miss, and it an important viewpoint to consider.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The book starts with the DARPA race, narrates the events, and stories of people who are shaping this story. GM, and Google play a very important role in the story. The book shines in presenting, well researching personal accounts from various actors like Red Whitaker, Chris Urmson, Sebastian Thrun, Larry Page, Antony Levandowski, Travis Kalanick, as well as many people from the top management in established car companies. It was good to get a first hand account on how people running established businesses think, and make decisions. It also shares the grit, and adventures of engineers who work to push the envelop of the possibilities. The book indirectly highlights the value/policy stances taken by companies such as Waymo, Tesla, and Uber pursuing self driving technology after giving the backround on the limitations of the technology, which were known to everyone developing it. It should be noted that as of 2019, Tesla and Uber have both been responsible for loss of lives with their pursuit of this adventure, and both have escaped consequences for their mistakes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;With all the events, book lays the solid ground for what is to come and expected in the next few years or decades for Autonomy. I will count this book as one of the good business books that I have read in recent years.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-autonomy-the-quest-to-build-the-driverless-car-and-how-it-will-reshape-our-world.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 16:40:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Indo-Arabic Number System</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/11/26/the-indo-arabic-number-system.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are two articles about inventions that were listed
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/11/24/book-review-the-greatest-inventions-of-the-past-2000-years.html"&gt;Book Review: The Greatest Inventions of the Past 2000 Years&lt;/a&gt; book that I wanted to note down in my blog for
future reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I wanted to note down is, I personally find that numeric system that we use today has stood the test of time
and is limitless. And my second reason could be due to a emotional attachment and association that is imbibed in me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V. S. Ramachandran&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
My favorite invention is the place-value notation system combined with the the user of a symbol 0 for zero to
denote a nonexistant number; this marks the birth of modern mathematics. This system was invented in India, probably
during the first millennium before Christ, but was first systematized by the Hindu mathematician and astronomer
Aryabhata I at the tail end of the  fifth century and then transmitted to the West via the Arabs (hence the phrase
"Arabic Numerals"). Before this time, even simple arithmetic was tedious and time-consuming (as when the Romans and
Greeks used the cumbersome "Roman numerals" - sometime still used in the west). And math, of course, is essential
for all science. Without the early invention of zero and place value as well as the use of the a symbol to denote
an unknown quantity in an equation (algebra), also from India, subsequent developments could not have occurred.
There would be no calculus, no newtonian or Galilean science, no computers, and essentially no modern world.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keith Devlin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"What is the most important invention in the past two thousand years?" is one of those questions that
no correct answer - like "What is the best novel / symphony / movie?" - But if I had to make a choice,
it would be the Hindu-Arabic number system, which reached essentially it's present form in the sixth
century. Without it, Galileo would have been unable to begin the quantificational study of nature which we
now call science, and we would not have had calculus, another major invention of the period in question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before of it's linguistic structure, the Hindu-Arabic number system allows humans who have an innate linguistic
fluency but only a very primitive number sense to use their ability with language to handle numbers of virtually
any useful magnitude, with as much precision as required. Today there is scarcely any aspect of life that
does not depend on our ability to handle numbers efficiently and accurately. True, we now use computers to
do much of our number crunching, but without the Hindu-Arabic number system we would not have any computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to it's use in arithmetic and science, the Hindu-Arabic number system is the only genuinely
universal language on earth - apart, perhaps, from the Windows Operating System, which has achieved
the near universal adoption of a conceptually and technologically poor product by the sheer force
of market dominance. By contrast, the Hindu-Arabic number system gained worldwide acceptance because
it is far better designed and much more efficient for human usage than any other number system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/11/26/the-indo-arabic-number-system.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 23:43:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Myth of a Strong Leader</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/the-myth-of-a-strong-leader.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Myth of a Strong Leader" by Archie Brown is from Bill Gates book recommendation. Pause a moment and think about the title. Every now and then you will hear something saying "Strong Leader", you  never hear people saying "we need a weak leader".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book's title is that, the concept of "Strong Leader" is a myth.
According to the book, an effective person works by collaboration, flexibility and never becomes a center point of decision making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gatesnotes.com/Books/The-Myth-of-the-Strong-Leader"&gt;Review link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/the-myth-of-a-strong-leader.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 02:51:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work - Amazon Book Link</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2010/10/09/the-pleasures-and-sorrows-of-work-amazon-book-link.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is editorial book appearing in this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="vt-p" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/037542444X/krondonet-20"&gt;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/037542444X/krondonet-20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It presents a very interesting view on how the perception of Work and Life  has changed over the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alain de Botton on The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work to shine a spotlight on the working world. I wanted to write a book that would open our eyes to the beauty and occasional horror of the working world—and I did this by looking at 10 different industries, a deliberately eclectic range from accountancy to engineering, from biscuit manufacture to logistics. The strangest thing about the world of work is the widespread expectation that our work should make us happy. For thousands of years, work was viewed as something to be done with as rapidly as possible and escaped in the imagination through alcohol or religion. Aristotle was the first of many philosophers to state that no one could be both free and obliged to earn a living. A more optimistic assessment of work had to wait until the eighteenth century and men like Jean-Jacques Rousseau and Benjamin Franklin, who for the first time argued that one's working life could be at the centre of any desire for happiness. It was during this century that our modern ideas about work were formed—at the very same time as our modern ideas about love and marriage took shape.  In the pre-modern age, it was assumed that no one could try to be in love and married: marriage was something one did for purely commercial reasons. Things were going well if you maintained a tepid friendship with your spouse. Meanwhile, love was something you did with your mistress, with pleasure untied to the responsibilities of child-rearing. Yet the new philosophers of love argued that one might actually aim to marry the person one was in love with rather than just have an affair. To this unusual idea was added the even more peculiar notion that one might work both for money and to realise one's dreams, an idea that replaced the previous assumption that the day job took care of the rent and anything more ambitious had to happen in one's spare time.  We are the heirs of these two very ambitious beliefs: that you can be in love and married, and in a job and having a good time. It has become as impossible for us to think that you could be out of work and happy as it had once seemed impossible for Aristotle to think that you could be employed and human. Thus is born The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work. —Alain de Botton&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2010/10/09/the-pleasures-and-sorrows-of-work-amazon-book-link.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2010 15:36:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Agony and the Ecstasy</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2008/12/13/the-agony-and-the-ecstasy.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That night, as he lay sleepless in bed, he thought. &lt;i&gt;"Life has bee good. God did not create me to abandon me. I have loved marble, yes and paint too. I have loved architecture, and poetry too. I have loved my family and my friends. I have loved God the forms of the earth and the heavens, and people too. I have loved life to the full, and now I love death as its natural termination. Il Magnifico would be happy: for me, the forces of destruction never overcame creativity" &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Agony_and_the_Ecstasy_(novel)"&gt;The Agony and the Ecstasy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2008/12/13/the-agony-and-the-ecstasy.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 23:34:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>