<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Senthil Kumaran (Posts about books-read-in-2018)</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/categories/books-read-in-2018.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 04:47:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Book Review: Stranger In a Strange Land</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-stranger-in-a-strange-land.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/350.Stranger_in_a_Strange_Land" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="Stranger in a Strange Land" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1156897088m/350.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/350.Stranger_in_a_Strange_Land"&gt;Stranger in a Strange Land&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/205.Robert_A_Heinlein"&gt;Robert A. Heinlein&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2652356341"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Wow, what a book. It goes into multiple topics like being human, politics, religion, love, sex, community, spirituality, entrepreneurship, money, influence, negotiation, strategy and "understanding" of it all.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This gave a new word "grok" to English speaking people, which roughly means to "understand thoroughly" and becoming one with the concept.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;One interesting thing about this science fiction is, it combined the real world concepts of business, stocks, politics, and ownership with imaginary situation where humans have already traveled to mars and there human of raised by martian among us. The details covering the rise of Mike to the status of a godman, and formation of his communion was fun read.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Just imagine how close is this quote "Thou art god, I am god. All that groks is god.” by Valentine Michael Smith to Sanskrit Verse "Tat Tvam Asi". &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The character Jubal Harshaw, attributes that one can explain away everything by holding on solipsism, and pantheism.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I was impressed with Robert Heinlein covering so many topics. I really enjoyed it.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books-read-in-2018</category><category>reviews</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-stranger-in-a-strange-land.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 14:29:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: The Myth of the Strong Leader - Political Leadership in the Modern Age</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-the-myth-of-the-strong-leader-political-leadership-in-the-modern-age.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25261938-the-myth-of-the-strong-leader" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="The Myth of the Strong Leader: Political Leadership in the Modern Age" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1459037482m/25261938.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25261938-the-myth-of-the-strong-leader"&gt;The Myth of the Strong Leader: Political Leadership in the Modern Age&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/157733.Archie_Brown"&gt;Archie Brown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2569462128"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This book covers a great deal on political leadership and helps the reader to understand the political landscape of multiple nations. The crux of this, it is not a strong leader that brings a net positive change, but a leader who is flexible, who understands the situation well, goes into the details, establishes that the processes, and follows it through that will bring the net positive change. The way, the different leaders have accomplished is quite varied, and depends on the situation and the time.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This book introduces some amazing real life characters like, Adolfo Suárez of spain who transformed the country to Democracy from the previously established monarchy in a peaceful manner. It also shares how Deng Xioping is the person behind the economic advancement of China from 1970 onward. It shares the perspective on how Fidel Castro overthrew the dictatorship in his country, and how lived by his principles, and did not accumulate any wealth for himself.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;One thing that struck with me, when this book was written, Obama was the president of USA, and even then, the system in place in USA was such that, no one particular person was ultimately responsible everything in the government. It has been understood that answer for "who controls the whitehouse of USA", seems " no one knows". This is not a snarky comment, but a statement that workings of the government in USA is very complex, and there are multiple forces in effect at any time, including political parties, supporters, lobbyists, and corporations with interests, and it will be too much to give credit and put focus on a single person.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This book covers lot. It covers Britain, USA, Europe, South America, South Africa, China, Russia, touches upon New-Zealand, India and other nations. The author explores how various leaders in these countries have shaped the political landscapes of these places for better.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books-read-in-2018</category><category>reviews</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-the-myth-of-the-strong-leader-political-leadership-in-the-modern-age.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 14:27:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: I am Home portraits of immigrant teenagers</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/12/30/book-review-i-am-home-portraits-of-immigrant-teenagers.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/39220117-i-am-home-portraits-of-immigrant-teenagers" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="I am Home portraits of immigrant teenagers" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1520977718m/39220117.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/39220117-i-am-home-portraits-of-immigrant-teenagers"&gt;I am Home portraits of immigrant teenagers&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/18745691.Erica_McConnell_Rachel_Neumann_and_Thi_Bui"&gt;Erica McConnell, Rachel Neumann and Thi Bui&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2646998322"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Memorable book. It covers the stories of teenagers various different parts of the world like Keren, Eritrea, San Salvador, Huehuetenango, and lots of places around the world, who are now studying in Oakland International High School, and share what they think, when they think of "Home".&lt;br&gt;Book does a very good job of portraying the diversity that exists in OIHS.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books-read-in-2018</category><category>reviews</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/12/30/book-review-i-am-home-portraits-of-immigrant-teenagers.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 01:50:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: The Best We Could Do</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/11/07/book-review-the-best-we-could-do.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29936927-the-best-we-could-do" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="The Best We Could Do" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1461818306m/29936927.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29936927-the-best-we-could-do"&gt;The Best We Could Do&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/7302080.Thi_Bui"&gt;Thi Bui&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2569462776"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is a personal memoir of the author, Thi Bui, as she tries to recollect her own story of coming to the US as
a refugee from Vietnam on a boat.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Fast forward many years, the author is well educated, accomplished
in life, settled in society, and has a family of her own. When she has her first child, she tries to associate
herself with her mother and her times in Vietnam and their family migration to the US. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It covers the
political history of Vietnam well, and how the ordinary people suffered, without any exception, both at the hands
 of external oppressors and from local oppressors alike. There was no way out, except to Run away. And, run they
 did, in search for stabler societies so they and their children at-least can have a chance to live.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It is a heart-wrenching story as she understands the story of her own mother, father, and the reason they become the way they are, the hardships and life that they have seen in other parts of the world, the risks they took, and ultimately, the best they could do for their children.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It is a family story, and it helps us understand our own parents better.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quotes that I liked from the book&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This - not any particular piece of Vietnamese culture - is my inheritance: the inexplicable need and
extraordinary ability to run when the shit hits the fan. My refugee reflex.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;― Thi Bui, The Best We Could Do&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To understand how my father became the way he was, I had to learn what happened to him as a little boy. It took a long time to learn the right questions to ask.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;― Thi Bui, The Best We Could Do&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books-read-in-2018</category><category>reviews</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/11/07/book-review-the-best-we-could-do.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 15:16:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review - Code: The Hidden Language of Computer Hardware and Software</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/10/22/book-review-code-the-hidden-language-of-computer-hardware-and-software.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1360513.Code" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="Code: The Hidden Language of Computer Hardware and Software" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1182986669m/1360513.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1360513.Code"&gt;Code: The Hidden Language of Computer Hardware and Software&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/25169.Charles_Petzold"&gt;Charles Petzold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1663434726"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is a highly influential book in the subject of how Computers work from ground up. They author deals with the subject and introduces computers as if they were a natural evolution of inventions that had already taken effect and had proved useful to the society.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;After introducing the various needs for communication, the author explains how it can achieved using bulbs, and then chips, and then how it is stored and done at the higher scale using Computers. He goes both in the Hardware as well as Software section of how computers work, and why we need operating systems and programming languages.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The section on float point arithmetic caught my attention and imagination completely. This was a lucid explanation on storing decimal valued numbers using binary digits.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I throughly enjoyed this, and is already helping me appreciate some of the basic concepts used in Computers and Computer Science.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books-read-in-2018</category><category>reviews</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/10/22/book-review-code-the-hidden-language-of-computer-hardware-and-software.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 13:40:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: The Hacker's Diet</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/10/22/book-review-the-hackers-diet.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2582000-the-hacker-s-diet" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="The Hacker's Diet: How to Lose Weight and Hair Through Stress and Poor Nutrition" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1200416202m/2582000.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2582000-the-hacker-s-diet"&gt;The Hacker's Diet: How to Lose Weight and Hair Through Stress and Poor Nutrition&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/34203.John_Walker"&gt;John Walker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2564932281"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is the first health book that I could not put down. This is the book that is helping me to manage my weight and my health. So, it is a life-saving book for me. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I was worried about my weight gain, and my lack of time to do exercises. I have 2 kids now and have an hour commute to my work. Both of these leave me with very less time to do exercises regularly, and I was constantly feeling worried about weight gain.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This book helped to break the problem into two.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;a) Managing Weight.&lt;br&gt;b) Doing Exercises.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For a), I completely understood how this can be controlled by paying attention to the Calorie intake. That' it. I adjusted my calories and I went back to -3KG within 3 weeks. I have goal to go -13 kgs further so that I can maintain my weight at a desirable number. I am into managing of my weight now.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Once that is done, I know the need and utility value for exercises and I will able to make time for it to live for longer so that I could continue doing whatever I like.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Rarely, self-help books have proved valuable to me. This the 2nd self-help book that I can say that, it has proved valuable to me and the concepts taught will remain with me for the rest of my life.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Thank you, John Walker.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books-read-in-2018</category><category>reviews</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/10/22/book-review-the-hackers-diet.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 13:21:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review - The Mysterious Affair At Styles</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/08/13/book-review-the-mysterious-affair-at-styles.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/39716791-the-mysterious-affair-at-styles" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="The Mysterious Affair At Styles" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1522848228m/39716791.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/39716791-the-mysterious-affair-at-styles"&gt;The Mysterious Affair At Styles&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/123715.Agatha_Christie"&gt;Agatha Christie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2492444701"&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Agatha Christie won the bet my with my reading of the book too. I could not figure out the murderer or figure out the plot. It may be hard or impossible for the reader to find the plot as the information that is shared with is limited and more information is revealed as the plot is disclosed.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It was an enjoyable book with the variety of characters and it took me a to mid-century England for the hours I was reading this book.&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books-read-in-2018</category><category>reviews</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/08/13/book-review-the-mysterious-affair-at-styles.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 14:47:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: Astrophysics for People in a Hurry</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/08/04/book-review-astrophysics-for-people-in-a-hurry.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32191710-astrophysics-for-people-in-a-hurry" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="Astrophysics for People in a Hurry" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1527255595m/32191710.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32191710-astrophysics-for-people-in-a-hurry"&gt;Astrophysics for People in a Hurry&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/12855.Neil_deGrasse_Tyson"&gt;Neil deGrasse Tyson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2482522880"&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I loved this book. This is a very short book, to the point, and explains the universe in simple terms. What I didn't expect and was a surprise to me was the Author's humorous anecdotes, completely relevant to the present day reader inserted between the concepts in the pages.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For e.g. It was funny to know that behind US Govt which consumes Helium for military and research, the next second highest consumer of "Helium" was Macy's for it's Macy's day parade.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It was startling to know that life as we understand in any form, the single-celled organism has started in existence only the last 2% of the history of the universe. The universe is very very old, very very big. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Often there is a question on "Is there life elsewhere in the universe?" - The more I read these kinds of books, the more I realize that "There is life elsewhere in the universe. Highly likely. It is inevitable that either Earthians discover the other life forms, and they discover the Earthians. Also, the timeline of advancement, the calamities that are possible in next thousand years, humankind will, of course, take the ship, explore, and start settling in various other parts of the universe. Thinking like this doesn't sound like fiction to me.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It was a great book. I will start looking out for Neil DeGrasse Tyson from now.&lt;p&gt;Here are some excerpts that I noted from the book. This one is about Einstein, and the kind of impact he had in our
understanding of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/ua8m0eenypplx1j/astrophysics1.jpg?dl=0" class="align-center" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/ua8m0eenypplx1j/astrophysics1.jpg?dl=0" style="width: 550px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this one is about Spherical shape for any object that we may encounter in the universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/0k0q7hzaokuf63j/astrophysics2.jpg?dl=0" class="align-center" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/0k0q7hzaokuf63j/astrophysics2.jpg?dl=0" style="width: 450px; height: 300px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books-read-in-2018</category><category>reviews</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/08/04/book-review-astrophysics-for-people-in-a-hurry.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 03:03:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: Yummy Sourashtra Recipe Book</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/07/14/book-review-yummy-sourashtra-recipe-book.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40729090-yummy-sourashtra" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="Yummy Sourashtra: Delicious Recipes from Sourashtra Community (2018)" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1530843551m/40729090.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40729090-yummy-sourashtra"&gt;Yummy Sourashtra: Delicious Recipes from Sourashtra Community&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/18177974.O_K_Ramesh_Babu_and_K_K_Kasthuri"&gt;O.K. Ramesh Babu and K.K Kasthuri&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2454475203"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This book is written by my parents, so my obvious bias there. It chooses many good Sourashtra Recipes and presents them. The presentation is good. The language, editing can be improved.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;The book in various different formats is available here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.yummysourashtra.com/recipe-book/"&gt;https://www.yummysourashtra.com/recipe-book/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books-read-in-2018</category><category>reviews</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/07/14/book-review-yummy-sourashtra-recipe-book.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 17:04:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: Chaos - Making a New Science</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/06/03/book-review-chaos-making-a-new-science.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36691904-chaos" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="Chaos: Making a New Science" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1512063964m/36691904.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36691904-chaos"&gt;Chaos: Making a New Science&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/10401.James_Gleick"&gt;James Gleick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2217154759"&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I got interested in reading this book after hearing about this from Robert Sapolsky in one of his lectures. He had a very high regard for this book and states it had a tremendous influence on him.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For me, I had to struggle reading this book. This introduces the field of Choas and presents the story and anecdotes of about 200 scientists who were involved with Choas. It's a challenge to present a cohesive story when someone is dealing with 200 investigators. I felt frequent disconnects between one paragraph after another. I could not follow the trail of the story, and in fact, I wondered if there is any story at all here. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The book tries to lay a case that even after understanding Classical physics, and Quantum physics, the scientists discovered new ways to reason about nature using non-linear equations which depended upon the initial conditions. The later part, the system of non-linear equations which depend upon the initial conditions is called as the Chaos Theory.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I noted down the following interesting quotes from this book.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“John Hubbard, exploring iterated functions and the infinite fractal wildness of the Mandelbrot set, considered chaos a poor name for his work, because it implied randomness. To him, the overriding message was that simple processes in nature could produce magnificent edifices of complexity without randomness. In nonlinearity and feedback lay all the necessary tools for encoding and then unfolding structures as rich as the human brain.”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“The Mandelbrot set obeys an extraordinarily precise scheme leaving nothing to chance whatsoever. I strongly suspect that the day somebody actually figures out how the brain is organized they will discover to their amazement that there is a coding scheme for building the brain which is of extraordinary precision. The idea of randomness in biology is just reflex.”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"Shallow ideas can be assimilated; ideas that require people to reorganize their picture of the world provoke hostility."&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books-read-in-2018</category><category>reviews</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/06/03/book-review-chaos-making-a-new-science.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 06:23:51 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>