<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Senthil Kumaran (Posts about books)</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/categories/books.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 05:13:21 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Book Review: The Manga Guide to Calculus</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/01/22/book-review-the-manga-guide-to-calculus.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6309077-the-manga-guide-to-calculus" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="The Manga Guide to Calculus" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1328753481l/6309077._SX98_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6309077-the-manga-guide-to-calculus"&gt;The Manga Guide to Calculus&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/2865700.Hiroyuki_Kojima"&gt;Hiroyuki Kojima&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2535927955"&gt;2 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I tried to pick up some high-level intuition on the basics of calculus with this book, but I failed. Unlike, other Manga guides on electricity, and linear algebra, I found this book not very strong on the plot and I felt it did not present the story in a cohesive manner. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The concepts were introduced randomly, and I could not see how one built upon the previously introduced concept. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;On the positive note, it did introduce very basics of calculus well, and I am eager to pick up other books on calculus with that foundation.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/1666575-senthil-kumaran"&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/01/22/book-review-the-manga-guide-to-calculus.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 14:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: Hackers and Painters by Paul Graham</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/01/22/book-review-hackers-and-painters-by-paul-graham.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41793.Hackers_Painters" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="Hackers &amp;amp; Painters: Big Ideas from the Computer Age" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1348562702l/41793._SX98_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41793.Hackers_Painters"&gt;Hackers &amp;amp; Painters: Big Ideas from the Computer Age&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/23551.Paul_Graham"&gt;Paul Graham&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/3133262402"&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Enjoyed reading Paul Graham's essays. It is quite dated, for e.g, lots of reference to Web in the 1990s, 2000s time when Yahoo was a prominent .com company. Some of his opinions on wealth creation are still applicable in 2020. But we have to read his essays with plenty of skepticism. He sings praise for lisp and instills some desire in the reader to study lisp and start a startup.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/1666575-senthil-kumaran"&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/01/22/book-review-hackers-and-painters-by-paul-graham.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 12:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: There There by Tommy Orange</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/01/22/book-review-there-there-by-tommy-orange.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36692478-there-there" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="There There" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1512071034l/36692478._SX98_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36692478-there-there"&gt;There There&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/17205711.Tommy_Orange"&gt;Tommy Orange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/3135501653"&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This book is one of it's kind. I had never come across a topic like this one. It reads like a monologue but dwells a lot into History and societal norms. It dwells in Native American history because the author is a native American, and explains his life story and story of his friends in a compelling manner. The incidents take place in Oakland, ca, and the reader familiar with the region can relate to many incidents narrated in the story. The story is an eye-opener for many to perceive the native American culture a little broadly and in a practical manner.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/1666575-senthil-kumaran"&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2020/01/22/book-review-there-there-by-tommy-orange.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 12:18:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: Kubernetes in Action by Marco Luksa</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2019/10/06/book-review-kubernetes-in-action-by-marco-luksa.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34013922-kubernetes-in-action" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="Kubernetes in Action" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1514938018l/34013922._SX98_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34013922-kubernetes-in-action"&gt;Kubernetes in Action&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/16353372.Marko_Luksa"&gt;Marko Luksa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/3003905449"&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This book explained the concepts behind Kubernetes well. It just did keep itself at the level of a book for an operator of Kubernetes and went into explaining what is happening underneath quite well.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2019/10/06/book-review-kubernetes-in-action-by-marco-luksa.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 05:36:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: They Called Us Enemy by George Takei</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2019/10/06/book-review-they-called-us-enemy-by-george-takei.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/42527866-they-called-us-enemy" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="They Called Us Enemy" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1541125895l/42527866._SX98_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/42527866-they-called-us-enemy"&gt;They Called Us Enemy&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/260482.George_Takei"&gt;George Takei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/3003892657"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This book is a straightforward narration by Georgia Takei of a Japanese Internment by the US Government during World War II. George and his family had suffered this cruelty. He highlights how opportunistic senators took chances to rise to power by promoting racial discrimination.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I had not known about this part of US history. I also did not know how ACLU helped the Japenese in the US then. US had detained 250,000 Japanese families living in the US, many of them US citizens, into camps during WWII.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Having lived through this horror, a lot of these Japanese families restarted and rebuilt their lives again. George Takei turned to activism to share his story with the masses, and I think he has been very effective.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This book has come the right time when similar mistreatment is being carried out by certain opportunistic politicians.&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2019/10/06/book-review-they-called-us-enemy-by-george-takei.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 05:29:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review - The Mahabharata: A Shortened Modern Prose Version of the Indian Epic</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2019/10/06/book-review-the-mahabharata-a-shortened-modern-prose-version-of-the-indian-epic.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20657408-the-mahabharata" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="The Mahabharata: A Shortened Modern Prose Version of the Indian Epic" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1391108802l/20657408._SX98_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20657408-the-mahabharata"&gt;The Mahabharata: A Shortened Modern Prose Version of the Indian Epic&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/1305302.R_K_Narayan"&gt;R.K. Narayan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/3003633849"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Mahabharata is one of the most complex stories I have ever read. I read this book following The Ramayana by R.K.Narayan. The ethical dilemmas presented in this story is at a whole different level than Ramayana. While in Ramayana, there are good guys and bad guys in Mahabharata there is nothing like that.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;No one is entirely good or no one is entirely bad. The Pandavas and Kauravas are brothers, just competing against each other, but their quarrel reaches to a level for war.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Coming to the war, which is an important topic of this story, the book has 3 chapters dedicated to the avoidance of war and only one chapter for the war.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In spite of suffering all the atrocities presented by Duryodhana, Pandavas realize that war is not good for anyone, and try for multiple attempts to prevent the war. Duryodhana plays politics and chooses to listen, and highlight points only which could give a chance for war.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And when it comes to war, Pandavas understands that a deterministic outcome is achieved by eliminating everyone in the enemy camp, even babies. So, after trying to avoid war, when the war becomes inevitable, Krisha proposes and leads a _genocide_ against the Kaurava clan.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To me, the most complex characters in this story were that of Karna and Krishna. &lt;br&gt;Karna has chances to prevent war, he understands his background well but still chooses to side with Duryodhana. Krishna is one who leads the Pandavas to war and gives guidance "on duties" in ambiguous times.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;There is no good or a bad person in this entire story.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2019/10/06/book-review-the-mahabharata-a-shortened-modern-prose-version-of-the-indian-epic.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 01:16:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: A Mind for Numbers by Barbara Oakley</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-a-mind-for-numbers-how-to-excel-at-math-and-science-even-if-you-flunked-algebra.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18693655-a-mind-for-numbers" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="A Mind for Numbers: How to Excel at Math and Science (Even If You Flunked Algebra)" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1387148777m/18693655.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18693655-a-mind-for-numbers"&gt;A Mind for Numbers: How to Excel at Math and Science&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/669905.Barbara_Oakley"&gt;Barbara Oakley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2535923139"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Like most readers, I stumbled upon this book after taking Barbara Oakley's Learning How to Learn Course in Coursera. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This book reinforces the concepts taught in that course. The idea of relaxed learning, giving ourselves plenty of time while learning difficult concepts, avoiding procrastination, and tools that help us avoid the procrastination. The idea of repetition for remembering different concepts is presented and stressed well this book.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The importance of sleep for learning stayed with me and changed me when I took the course based on this book. I never discount sleep for important exams or deadlines now.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The crux of learning is expressed well by this quote from Santiago Ramón y Cajal introduced to us in this book&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br&gt;What a wonderful stimulant it would be for the beginner if his instructor, instead of amazing and dismaying him with the sublimity of great past achievements, would reveal instead the origin of each scientific discovery, the series of errors and missteps that preceded it - information that, from a human perspective, is essential to an accurate explanation of discovery. &lt;/i&gt; - &lt;b&gt;Santiago Ramón y Cajal&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-a-mind-for-numbers-how-to-excel-at-math-and-science-even-if-you-flunked-algebra.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 15:50:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review - The Ramayana By R.K. Narayan</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-the-ramayana-by-rk-narayan.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/129876.The_Ramayana" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="The Ramayana: A Shortened Modern Prose Version of the Indian Epic" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1309283297m/129876.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/129876.The_Ramayana"&gt;The Ramayana: A Shortened Modern Prose Version of the Indian Epic&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/1305302.R_K_Narayan"&gt;R.K. Narayan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2771509811"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is Narayan's narration of the famous Indian Epic, Ramayana. It follows Valmiki's script, instead of the Kamban, that I thought, I would expect from the South Indian author. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The introduction gives the details of the Ramanand Sagar's Television series and how India stood still when Ramayan was telecast on weekends. The story is well know, but the best part of this book are in the details.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I liked the chapter on Vali and Sugreeva, wherein the author does not mince words and shares about the ethical lapse of Rama. That was a difficult chapter in Ramayana. Rama tries to help Sugreeva to fight against his brother Vali. He kills Vali by hiding. Rama being a warrior, is supposed to fight straight, and being righteous person, who is supposed to not harm anyone unnecessarily, forgoes both in this episode. Vali questions him about this. And Rama rationalizes that Vali is not a sub-human, Monkey, but a higher form since he possesses the judgement skills of Right vs Wrong, and since Vali choose the Wrong approaches, when knowing what was Right, he had to meet with this fate. Also, by having killed by Rama, Vali is elevated to higher form in his death.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Other mistakes of Rama are explained as a consequence of Rama forgetting his inherent divinity, making mistakes as a human, and needed constant reminders from gods. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This book is action packed, has good stories, morals, stories of ethical dilemmas and is entertaining. The author does a very good job of maintaining balance of religious piety and story telling in this book. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-the-ramayana-by-rk-narayan.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 21:43:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review:  The Smart Girl's Guide to Privacy: Practical Tips for Staying Safe Online</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-the-smart-girls-guide-to-privacy-practical-tips-for-staying-safe-online.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25644910-the-smart-girl-s-guide-to-privacy" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="The Smart Girl's Guide to Privacy: Practical Tips for Staying Safe Online" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1433187260m/25644910.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25644910-the-smart-girl-s-guide-to-privacy"&gt;The Smart Girl's Guide to Privacy: Practical Tips for Staying Safe Online&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/50868.Violet_Blue"&gt;Violet Blue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2735463770"&gt;3 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is a checklist book for the various steps that a person can take to stay secure and manage their privacy online. This is written for general populace, and does a good work to highlights of perils of getting hacked online, problems associated with online privacy. Author provides references to tools and mechanisms that can help person stay safe online.&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-the-smart-girls-guide-to-privacy-practical-tips-for-staying-safe-online.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 17:01:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review - Autonomy: The Quest to Build the Driverless Car — And How It Will Reshape Our World</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-autonomy-the-quest-to-build-the-driverless-car-and-how-it-will-reshape-our-world.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autonomy: The Quest to Build the Driverless Car—And How It Will Reshape Our World by Lawrence D. Burns,  Christopher Shulgan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36039329-autonomy" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="Autonomy: The Quest to Build the Driverless Car—And How It Will Reshape Our World" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1531803242m/36039329.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36039329-autonomy"&gt;Autonomy: The Quest to Build the Driverless Car—And How It Will Reshape Our World&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3189685.Lawrence_D_Burns"&gt;Lawrence D. Burns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2652404433"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This book reminded me of "The Road Ahead" by Bill Gates. This is an impressive account on Self Driving Technology, that is about to come and consume us in the near future. The book is very well written. Initially, I had plenty of doubts on the author, Lawrence D Burn's style, thinking that he was one of the pure management type guys, looking at things in a disconnected way, trying to associate himself with changes brought about by others. I was proven wrong. I started appreciating his insights, his outlook towards this project, his commitments, and really understood where he was coming from when the author provided more context into his own up bringing and background. He provided the view from Detroit, that many following the self-driving space will miss, and it an important viewpoint to consider.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The book starts with the DARPA race, narrates the events, and stories of people who are shaping this story. GM, and Google play a very important role in the story. The book shines in presenting, well researching personal accounts from various actors like Red Whitaker, Chris Urmson, Sebastian Thrun, Larry Page, Antony Levandowski, Travis Kalanick, as well as many people from the top management in established car companies. It was good to get a first hand account on how people running established businesses think, and make decisions. It also shares the grit, and adventures of engineers who work to push the envelop of the possibilities. The book indirectly highlights the value/policy stances taken by companies such as Waymo, Tesla, and Uber pursuing self driving technology after giving the backround on the limitations of the technology, which were known to everyone developing it. It should be noted that as of 2019, Tesla and Uber have both been responsible for loss of lives with their pursuit of this adventure, and both have escaped consequences for their mistakes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;With all the events, book lays the solid ground for what is to come and expected in the next few years or decades for Autonomy. I will count this book as one of the good business books that I have read in recent years.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/book-review-autonomy-the-quest-to-build-the-driverless-car-and-how-it-will-reshape-our-world.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 16:40:10 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>