<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Senthil Kumaran's thoughts. (Posts about books)</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/categories/books.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 01:40:51 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Book Review: Indian Astronomy - A Primer</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/11/26/book-review-indian-astronomy-a-primer.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36098268-indian-astronomy---a-primer" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="Indian Astronomy - A Primer" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1503333685m/36098268.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36098268-indian-astronomy---a-primer"&gt;Indian Astronomy - A Primer&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/17116356.Dr_S_Balachandra_Rao"&gt;Dr. S. Balachandra Rao&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2196009327"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I read this book after I had completed reading the book &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1212151.The_Greatest_Inventions_of_the_Past_2_000_Years" rel="nofollow"&gt;The Greatest Inventions of the Past 2,000 Years&lt;/a&gt;. In that, I noted down the contributions of &lt;a href="http://xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/11/26/the-indo-arabic-number-system.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;The Indo-Arabic Number System&lt;/a&gt; as one of the significant inventions in the past 2000 years.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The important thing to note was, the positional value number system along with 0 was invented a 1000 years before the birth of Christ and it was systematized by &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aryabhata#Place_value_system_and_zero" rel="nofollow"&gt;Aryabhatta&lt;/a&gt; in the year 499 CE.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This greatly increased my curiosity for Indian mathematics. The book was a boon in that regard. It dwells with the Indian Astronomy, mathematics with a verifiable accuracy. We are given a survey of Astronomy in &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vedas" rel="nofollow"&gt;, &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hindu_astrology" rel="nofollow"&gt; Vedanga Jyotisa &lt;/a&gt;, Siddhantha (established truth), and giving the information about Aryabhatta I, Bhaskaracharya. It goes into details about Zodiacs and constellations (as calculated by the astronomers), Yuga System and Eras.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I came to know that Kali Yuga commenced on 17/18 February 3102 BCE, at the demise of Krishna. &lt;br&gt;So, as of this writing of the review, we have been living in **5119 years** since the start of Kali Yuga (an epoch).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The book also introduced me to the concept of Luni-solar months, were lunar months are pegged upon to solar months. The metric value is called Ahargana,. In Sanskrit 'ahoratra' means one full day and 'gana' means count. Hence, the Ahargana on any given day stands for the number of lunar days that have elapsed starting from an epoch. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This is the counting system used in Indian calendars. After giving details about this, book then talks about Co-ordinate systems, Rasi and Naksatra systems, Panchanga (Panchaga means 5 parts which are Tithi, Naksatra, Vara, Yoga and Karana) and gives the reference for the calculation mean positions of Sun, Moon and Planets. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Given the words like "Panchanga", "Tithi" etc, one would expect this book to be written by some astrologer or might have some preachiness to it. This is where, I think, the book shines. No, it has none of the preachiness, it has none of the emotional or venerable expressions towards those concepts. Instead, those are presented as Indian mathematics, by done mathematicians in India when as they pursued their understanding of the universe and recorded them.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The book is written by &lt;a href="ftp://ftp.gwdg.de/pub/EMIS/mirror/IMU/Elections_2002/ICHM/raocv.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;Dr. S. Balachandra Rao&lt;/a&gt; is was a professor of Mathematics, who has published around 20 books in subjects ranging from Numerical methods, differential equations, calculus, Indian Astronomy, and mathematics.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/11/26/book-review-indian-astronomy-a-primer.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 01:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Indo-Arabic Number System</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/11/26/the-indo-arabic-number-system.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are two articles about inventions that were listed
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/11/24/book-review-the-greatest-inventions-of-the-past-2000-years.html"&gt;Book Review: The Greatest Inventions of the Past 2000 Years&lt;/a&gt; book that I wanted to note down in my blog for
future reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I wanted to note down is, I personally find that numeric system that we use today has stood the test of time
and is limitless. And my second reason could be due to a emotional attachment and association that is imbibed in me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V. S. Ramachandran&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
My favorite invention is the place-value notation system combined with the the user of a symbol 0 for zero to
denote a nonexistant number; this marks the birth of modern mathematics. This system was invented in India, probably
during the first millennium before Christ, but was first systematized by the Hindu mathematician and astronomer
Aryabhata I at the tail end of the  fifth century and then transmitted to the West via the Arabs (hence the phrase
"Arabic Numerals"). Before this time, even simple arithmetic was tedious and time-consuming (as when the Romans and
Greeks used the cumbersome "Roman numerals" - sometime still used in the west). And math, of course, is essential
for all science. Without the early invention of zero and place value as well as the use of the a symbol to denote
an unknown quantity in an equation (algebra), also from India, subsequent developments could not have occurred.
There would be no calculus, no newtonian or Galilean science, no computers, and essentially no modern world.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keith Devlin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"What is the most important invention in the past two thousand years?" is one of those questions that
no correct answer - like "What is the best novel / symphony / movie?" - But if I had to make a choice,
it would be the Hindu-Arabic number system, which reached essentially it's present form in the sixth
century. Without it, Galileo would have been unable to begin the quantificational study of nature which we
now call science, and we would not have had calculus, another major invention of the period in question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before of it's linguistic structure, the Hindu-Arabic number system allows humans who have an innate linguistic
fluency but only a very primitive number sense to use their ability with language to handle numbers of virtually
any useful magnitude, with as much precision as required. Today there is scarcely any aspect of life that
does not depend on our ability to handle numbers efficiently and accurately. True, we now use computers to
do much of our number crunching, but without the Hindu-Arabic number system we would not have any computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to it's use in arithmetic and science, the Hindu-Arabic number system is the only genuinely
universal language on earth - apart, perhaps, from the Windows Operating System, which has achieved
the near universal adoption of a conceptually and technologically poor product by the sheer force
of market dominance. By contrast, the Hindu-Arabic number system gained worldwide acceptance because
it is far better designed and much more efficient for human usage than any other number system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/11/26/the-indo-arabic-number-system.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 23:43:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Three Men in a Boat</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/10/26/three-men-in-a-boat.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4921.Three_Men_in_a_Boat" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="Three Men in a Boat (Three Men, #1)" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1392791656m/4921.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4921.Three_Men_in_a_Boat"&gt;Three Men in a Boat&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3352.Jerome_K_Jerome"&gt;Jerome K. Jerome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2164386929"&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Funny writing. Made me chuckle at times and was very imaginative. makes for a light hearted reading.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started reading this book using a hardcopy that I had for long time. For convenience, I quickly finished by reading the online ebook at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.gutenberg.org/files/308/308-h/308-h.htm"&gt;Project Gutenberg&lt;/a&gt; . Since I read fast, I did't enjoy this very much. Won't discuss this much.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/10/26/three-men-in-a-boat.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 11:02:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Collapsing Universe</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/09/25/the-collapsing-universe.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1290985.The_Collapsing_Universe" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="The Collapsing Universe: The Story of Black Holes" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1464362010m/1290985.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1290985.The_Collapsing_Universe"&gt;The Collapsing Universe: The Story of Black Holes&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/16667.Isaac_Asimov"&gt;Isaac Asimov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2135003041"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Good Doctor once again explains Cosmology in lucid terms. He starts off with simple premises, known facts, composes and slowly leads up to higher concepts, ultimately leading to the concept of "Black Hole". The book had a "trill" factor to it, as we discover the nature of black holes and what constitutes a black hole and how the universe might have formed.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I was "wow"ed by this book.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some exciting learning here with this book. I learnt about the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cygnus_X-1"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cygnus_X-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/chandra/multimedia/cygnusx1.html"&gt;https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/chandra/multimedia/cygnusx1.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chandra_X-ray_Observatory"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chandra_X-ray_Observatory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schwarzschild_radius"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schwarzschild_radius&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karl_Schwarzschild"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karl_Schwarzschild&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>asimov</category><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/09/25/the-collapsing-universe.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 17:41:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Finished Reading: The Chip by T.R.Reid</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/07/11/finished-reading-the-chip-by-trreid.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Chip: How Two Americans Invented the Microchip and Launched a Revolution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the story Semi-conductor revolution pioneered by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Noyce"&gt;Robert Noyce&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_Kilby"&gt;Jack Kilby&lt;/a&gt; Author has done an excellent job of explaining the contribution of
these engineers and success of American Industry as a result of these individuals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/07/11/finished-reading-the-chip-by-trreid.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 02:07:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Finished Reading: The Meaning Of It All - Richard Feynman</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/04/03/finished-reading-the-meaning-of-it-all-richard-feynman.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/w6ilwgd9niepm8c/meaning_of_it_all.png" class="align-center" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/w6ilwgd9niepm8c/meaning_of_it_all.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a short non-technical book consisting of compiled speeches of Richard Feynman. It does not into physics, but
covers a lot of topics like religion, politics, society, ethical questions in science, atom bombs and scientist
motivations. Richard feynman has lot of context to explore all these areas. Plus, his communication style is very
pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually avoid reading general books like this. But I happen to pick this up, and on a day, when I was about to give
some leeway into an astrology (it's not a science) shared by my close ones, having just reading a topic in this book
gave me excellent points to bring my thinking back into track. Contrary to my assumption when starting to read this
book, I found it extremely useful!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/04/03/finished-reading-the-meaning-of-it-all-richard-feynman.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 17:29:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Myth of a Strong Leader</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/the-myth-of-a-strong-leader.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Myth of a Strong Leader" by Archie Brown is from Bill Gates book recommendation. Pause a moment and think about the title. Every now and then you will hear something saying "Strong Leader", you  never hear people saying "we need a weak leader".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book's title is that, the concept of "Strong Leader" is a myth.
According to the book, an effective person works by collaboration, flexibility and never becomes a center point of decision making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gatesnotes.com/Books/The-Myth-of-the-Strong-Leader"&gt;Review link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/the-myth-of-a-strong-leader.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 02:51:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work - Amazon Book Link</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2010/10/09/the-pleasures-and-sorrows-of-work-amazon-book-link.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is editorial book appearing in this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="vt-p" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/037542444X/krondonet-20"&gt;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/037542444X/krondonet-20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It presents a very interesting view on how the perception of Work and Life  has changed over the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alain de Botton on The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work to shine a spotlight on the working world. I wanted to write a book that would open our eyes to the beauty and occasional horror of the working world—and I did this by looking at 10 different industries, a deliberately eclectic range from accountancy to engineering, from biscuit manufacture to logistics. The strangest thing about the world of work is the widespread expectation that our work should make us happy. For thousands of years, work was viewed as something to be done with as rapidly as possible and escaped in the imagination through alcohol or religion. Aristotle was the first of many philosophers to state that no one could be both free and obliged to earn a living. A more optimistic assessment of work had to wait until the eighteenth century and men like Jean-Jacques Rousseau and Benjamin Franklin, who for the first time argued that one's working life could be at the centre of any desire for happiness. It was during this century that our modern ideas about work were formed—at the very same time as our modern ideas about love and marriage took shape.  In the pre-modern age, it was assumed that no one could try to be in love and married: marriage was something one did for purely commercial reasons. Things were going well if you maintained a tepid friendship with your spouse. Meanwhile, love was something you did with your mistress, with pleasure untied to the responsibilities of child-rearing. Yet the new philosophers of love argued that one might actually aim to marry the person one was in love with rather than just have an affair. To this unusual idea was added the even more peculiar notion that one might work both for money and to realise one's dreams, an idea that replaced the previous assumption that the day job took care of the rent and anything more ambitious had to happen in one's spare time.  We are the heirs of these two very ambitious beliefs: that you can be in love and married, and in a job and having a good time. It has become as impossible for us to think that you could be out of work and happy as it had once seemed impossible for Aristotle to think that you could be employed and human. Thus is born The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work. —Alain de Botton&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2010/10/09/the-pleasures-and-sorrows-of-work-amazon-book-link.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2010 15:36:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Agony and the Ecstasy</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2008/12/13/the-agony-and-the-ecstasy.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That night, as he lay sleepless in bed, he thought. &lt;i&gt;"Life has bee good. God did not create me to abandon me. I have loved marble, yes and paint too. I have loved architecture, and poetry too. I have loved my family and my friends. I have loved God the forms of the earth and the heavens, and people too. I have loved life to the full, and now I love death as its natural termination. Il Magnifico would be happy: for me, the forces of destruction never overcame creativity" &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Agony_and_the_Ecstasy_(novel)"&gt;The Agony and the Ecstasy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2008/12/13/the-agony-and-the-ecstasy.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 23:34:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Books I could read this year</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2007/12/31/books-i-could-read-this-year.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li&gt; Men who made new physics. &lt;br&gt;

It is story of the physicists who heralded the new era of physics.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Five Dollar Smile. &lt;br&gt;

One of the early writings of Shashi Tharoor, perhaps when he was in college. Stories feature subjects which occupy adolescent minds. Subjects like friendship, love, sex and politics are dealt with in a very comical way.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; How I taught my grandma and other stories. &lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Old man and his god. &lt;br&gt;

Both the books by madam Sudha Murty. Most of the stories upheld values, virtuous nature in human beings, human dignity, many ethical and philanthropic subjects. &lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Its not about Bike. &lt;br&gt;

It is all about strength and courage by the cyclist, marathon guy Lance Armstrong, who defeated cancer to get back to race and win the Tour de France 5 times.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Just do it. &lt;br&gt;

Very practical advice from Sir. Richard Branson. He just did the Virgin empire and encourages everyone to just do what one wants to do. &lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Bridges of Madison County.&lt;br&gt;

Very romantic one. In fact, the best romantic book I have read so far. Writing is very good and it is a subject which could lie on the borderline of love and infidelity, but author has dealt it in a wonderful way that the reader can understand and sometimes agree with the borderline which it portrays.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Guide to Earth, Moon and Space. &lt;br&gt;

Asimov's non-fiction writing. His writing is very lucid and it tries to bring back the questions that a curious child wonders when standing outside and looking at the night sky. Questions like, &lt;i&gt;"What are those shiny things?, Why is it there?, Why is not falling?, Why are so many of them there?, Why is it dark now?, Is sun asleep?, When we travel in a scooter how come moon is also traveling along with us?Can we race ahead of it?"&lt;/i&gt;. Those are just fun and very valid questions. Asimov tries to answer them all as it can be understood by the child who asks those questions. The book is simply too good. I really loved it.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Theory of Everything.&lt;br&gt;

Stephen Hawkings explains science as it evolved from the times of Galileo till the string theory. It is easy to read, and presented in a very concise manner.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Revenge of the Baby Sat.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Calvin and Hobbes 1st book.&lt;br&gt;

Both of them, lovable Calvin and Hobbes adventures.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Asterix series.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt; Asterix the Gaul

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Asterix and the Golden Sickel

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Asterix and the Goths.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Asterix and the Chieftains Shield.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; The Mansions of the Gods.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Asterix and the Soothsayer.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Asterix and Caesar's Gift.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Fantastic Voyage. &lt;br&gt;

Asimov's fiction, which is, in fact is based on the screenplay of a movie by the same name. The book came much earlier than the movie. Three men and a woman, miniature themselves and enter inside the human body,in a miniaturized submarine to do an operation. They will have complete the operation and get out of body within a time limit, otherwise even as their goal fails, everyone stands at a danger of losing something very valuable, the information available with the person they are trying to save at any cost.

Asimov has taken take to write fiction in very logical way. Like the troop experience the "Brownian Motion" as they enter inside the body. &lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Out of my Comfort Zone. &lt;br&gt;

Steve Waugh's Biography. While reading this, I had many fits of laughter, many a moments of amusement and wonder at this simple guy with lot of character. Steve is definitely one of my favorite sports person. He is very plain and direct. And a very bold person too as we can see in his auto-biography. Good lessons on leadership and management is presented in his book.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Krishna and Gopal.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Savitri&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Buddhist Tales&lt;br&gt;

From Amar Chitra Katha series, based on folklore, mythology and ancient Indian stories. They deal the moral values, justice, ethical leadership and administration. &lt;br&gt;

I have more Amar Chitra Katha books to read.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Hound of Baskervilles.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Sign of Four &lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Study in Scarlet &lt;br&gt;

Those were the brilliance of Sir. Arthur Canon Doyle through Sherlock Holmes and Dr. Watson. I read these for the second time as I had completed the sherlock holmes series a long time back.



&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of these books, like "Guide to Earth, Moon and Space", "Theory of Everything", Sherlock Holmes series, I read along with my friend Avinash and we both enjoyed it together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from these, there are few technical books, I could &lt;i&gt;lay my hands upon&lt;i&gt;. Note , technical books are not meant to be read, they are to be studied thoroughly and worked upon a number of times. So, I cannot put them in the read category.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could get chance to work with,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt; Version Control with Subversion by Ben Collins-Sussman,

Brian W. Fitzpatrick, C. Michael Pilato.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Word power made easy by Norman Lewis.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Cryptography and Network Security, by William Stallings.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://aarthimuralidharan.blogspot.com"&gt;My friend&lt;/a&gt; and I had thought at the start of year to compete for the &lt;a href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2007/12/31/www.livejournal.com/community/50bookchallenge"&gt;50bookchallenge&lt;/a&gt;. While that was my list of books, I am glad that we got started and next year, I plan to read at least 50 books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you would like to read any of these books, I would be glad to share it with you. You can also have a peek into my online library at &lt;a href="http://books.google.co.in/books?as_list=BDQiZH8QQiLL-oPzi3N_xARoUPZY8CAHGfBKJvMKvuOm5YfglkA8"&gt;books.google.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year 2008 to all!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2007/12/31/books-i-could-read-this-year.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 05:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>