<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Senthil Kumaran's thoughts. (Posts about books)</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/categories/books.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 15:26:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Book Review: The Best We Could Do</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/11/07/book-review-the-best-we-could-do.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29936927-the-best-we-could-do" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="The Best We Could Do" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1461818306m/29936927.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29936927-the-best-we-could-do"&gt;The Best We Could Do&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/7302080.Thi_Bui"&gt;Thi Bui&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2569462776"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is a personal memoir of the author, Thi Bui, as she tries to recollect her own story of coming to the US as
a refugee from Vietnam on a boat.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Fast forward many years, the author is well educated, accomplished
in life, settled in society, and has a family of her own. When she has her first child, she tries to associate
herself with her mother and her times in Vietnam and their family migration to the US. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It covers the
political history of Vietnam well, and how the ordinary people suffered, without any exception, both at the hands
 of external oppressors and from local oppressors alike. There was no way out, except to Run away. And, run they
 did, in search for stabler societies so they and their children at-least can have a chance to live.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It is a heart-wrenching story as she understands the story of her own mother, father, and the reason they become the way they are, the hardships and life that they have seen in other parts of the world, the risks they took, and ultimately, the best they could do for their children.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It is a family story, and it helps us understand our own parents better.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quotes that I liked from the book&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This - not any particular piece of Vietnamese culture - is my inheritance: the inexplicable need and
extraordinary ability to run when the shit hits the fan. My refugee reflex.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;― Thi Bui, The Best We Could Do&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To understand how my father became the way he was, I had to learn what happened to him as a little boy. It took a long time to learn the right questions to ask.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;― Thi Bui, The Best We Could Do&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/11/07/book-review-the-best-we-could-do.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 15:16:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review - Code: The Hidden Language of Computer Hardware and Software</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/10/22/book-review-code-the-hidden-language-of-computer-hardware-and-software.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1360513.Code" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="Code: The Hidden Language of Computer Hardware and Software" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1182986669m/1360513.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1360513.Code"&gt;Code: The Hidden Language of Computer Hardware and Software&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/25169.Charles_Petzold"&gt;Charles Petzold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1663434726"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is a highly influential book in the subject of how Computers work from ground up. They author deals with the subject and introduces computers as if they were a natural evolution of inventions that had already taken effect and had proved useful to the society.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;After introducing the various needs for communication, the author explains how it can achieved using bulbs, and then chips, and then how it is stored and done at the higher scale using Computers. He goes both in the Hardware as well as Software section of how computers work, and why we need operating systems and programming languages.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The section on float point arithmetic caught my attention and imagination completely. This was a lucid explanation on storing decimal valued numbers using binary digits.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I throughly enjoyed this, and is already helping me appreciate some of the basic concepts used in Computers and Computer Science.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/10/22/book-review-code-the-hidden-language-of-computer-hardware-and-software.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 13:40:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: The Hacker's Diet</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/10/22/book-review-the-hackers-diet.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2582000-the-hacker-s-diet" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="The Hacker's Diet: How to Lose Weight and Hair Through Stress and Poor Nutrition" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1200416202m/2582000.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2582000-the-hacker-s-diet"&gt;The Hacker's Diet: How to Lose Weight and Hair Through Stress and Poor Nutrition&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/34203.John_Walker"&gt;John Walker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2564932281"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is the first health book that I could not put down. This is the book that is helping me to manage my weight and my health. So, it is a life-saving book for me. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I was worried about my weight gain, and my lack of time to do exercises. I have 2 kids now and have an hour commute to my work. Both of these leave me with very less time to do exercises regularly, and I was constantly feeling worried about weight gain.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This book helped to break the problem into two.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;a) Managing Weight.&lt;br&gt;b) Doing Exercises.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For a), I completely understood how this can be controlled by paying attention to the Calorie intake. That' it. I adjusted my calories and I went back to -3KG within 3 weeks. I have goal to go -13 kgs further so that I can maintain my weight at a desirable number. I am into managing of my weight now.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Once that is done, I know the need and utility value for exercises and I will able to make time for it to live for longer so that I could continue doing whatever I like.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Rarely, self-help books have proved valuable to me. This the 2nd self-help book that I can say that, it has proved valuable to me and the concepts taught will remain with me for the rest of my life.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Thank you, John Walker.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/10/22/book-review-the-hackers-diet.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 13:21:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: Astrophysics for People in a Hurry</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/08/04/book-review-astrophysics-for-people-in-a-hurry.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32191710-astrophysics-for-people-in-a-hurry" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="Astrophysics for People in a Hurry" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1527255595m/32191710.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32191710-astrophysics-for-people-in-a-hurry"&gt;Astrophysics for People in a Hurry&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/12855.Neil_deGrasse_Tyson"&gt;Neil deGrasse Tyson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2482522880"&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I loved this book. This is a very short book, to the point, and explains the universe in simple terms. What I didn't expect and was a surprise to me was the Author's humorous anecdotes, completely relevant to the present day reader inserted between the concepts in the pages.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For e.g. It was funny to know that behind US Govt which consumes Helium for military and research, the next second highest consumer of "Helium" was Macy's for it's Macy's day parade.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It was startling to know that life as we understand in any form, the single-celled organism has started in existence only the last 2% of the history of the universe. The universe is very very old, very very big. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Often there is a question on "Is there life elsewhere in the universe?" - The more I read these kinds of books, the more I realize that "There is life elsewhere in the universe. Highly likely. It is inevitable that either Earthians discover the other life forms, and they discover the Earthians. Also, the timeline of advancement, the calamities that are possible in next thousand years, humankind will, of course, take the ship, explore, and start settling in various other parts of the universe. Thinking like this doesn't sound like fiction to me.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It was a great book. I will start looking out for Neil DeGrasse Tyson from now.&lt;p&gt;Here are some excerpts that I noted from the book. This one is about Einstein, and the kind of impact he had in our
understanding of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/ua8m0eenypplx1j/astrophysics1.jpg?dl=0" class="align-center" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/ua8m0eenypplx1j/astrophysics1.jpg?dl=0" style="width: 550px; height: 300px;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this one is about Spherical shape for any object that we may encounter in the universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/0k0q7hzaokuf63j/astrophysics2.jpg?dl=0" class="align-center" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/0k0q7hzaokuf63j/astrophysics2.jpg?dl=0" style="width: 450px; height: 300px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><category>reviews</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/08/04/book-review-astrophysics-for-people-in-a-hurry.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 03:03:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review: Yummy Sourashtra Recipe Book</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/07/14/book-review-yummy-sourashtra-recipe-book.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40729090-yummy-sourashtra" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="Yummy Sourashtra: Delicious Recipes from Sourashtra Community (2018)" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1530843551m/40729090.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40729090-yummy-sourashtra"&gt;Yummy Sourashtra: Delicious Recipes from Sourashtra Community&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/18177974.O_K_Ramesh_Babu_and_K_K_Kasthuri"&gt;O.K. Ramesh Babu and K.K Kasthuri&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2454475203"&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This book is written by my parents, so my obvious bias there. It chooses many good Sourashtra Recipes and presents them. The presentation is good. The language, editing can be improved.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;The book in various different formats is available here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.yummysourashtra.com/recipe-book/"&gt;https://www.yummysourashtra.com/recipe-book/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/07/14/book-review-yummy-sourashtra-recipe-book.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 17:04:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Book Review - Manga Guide to Linear Algebra</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/04/07/book-review-manga-guide-to-linear-algebra.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13227038-the-manga-guide-to-linear-algebra" style="float: left; padding-right: 20px"&gt;&lt;img border="0" alt="The Manga Guide to Linear Algebra" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1344690423m/13227038.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13227038-the-manga-guide-to-linear-algebra"&gt;The Manga Guide to Linear Algebra&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/653728.Shin_Takahashi"&gt;Shin Takahashi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2353816790"&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Manga Guide to Linear Algebra is a manga comic that teaches linear algebra concept. When I stumbled upon the terms Eigenvalues and Eigenvectors, I found those were greek to me, and I had no intuitive understanding of those terms. I decided to spend 4-hours to read about the basics of linear algebra from this book.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The book starts with the concept of sets, functions, and relations. Then introduces matrices, and then vectors. It gives a gentle introduction to various matrix operations. Gives visual clue on vector representations. Introduces the concept of linear dependence and linear independence in vectors.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Shows the examples of linear transformations which are practical applications of linear algebra and finally goes to introduce eigenvalues and eigenvectors. Finally, for Eigenvalues and Eigenvectors, these are the examples that are shown.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a example of 2x2 matrix for illustrating Eigenvectors given in the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
c_1[3, 1] + c_2[1, 2] [[8 -3]     -&amp;gt; c1[21, 7] + c_2[2, 4]
                       [2  1]]

c_1[3, 1] + c_2[1, 2] -&amp;gt; f[[8 -3]    -&amp;gt; c_1[7 [3, 1]] + c_2[2 [1, 2]]
                           [2  1]]
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image of the expression using the linear transformation, expressed using the same original vectors, but with
coefficients, 7 and 2 now. Then gives the example of 3 dimentional vector, and finally explains the the concept of
Eigenvalue and Eigenvectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the above example, 7 and 2 are eigenvalues, and (3, 1) and (1, 2) are the eigenvectors associated with those eigen
values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word &lt;cite&gt;eigen&lt;/cite&gt; seems to have come from german which means proper or characteristic.  It seems that we express the
original expression with the linear transformation properly using some values and vectors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2018/04/07/book-review-manga-guide-to-linear-algebra.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 19:24:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Indo-Arabic Number System</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/11/26/the-indo-arabic-number-system.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are two articles about inventions that were listed
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/11/24/book-review-the-greatest-inventions-of-the-past-2000-years.html"&gt;Book Review: The Greatest Inventions of the Past 2000 Years&lt;/a&gt; book that I wanted to note down in my blog for
future reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I wanted to note down is, I personally find that numeric system that we use today has stood the test of time
and is limitless. And my second reason could be due to a emotional attachment and association that is imbibed in me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V. S. Ramachandran&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
My favorite invention is the place-value notation system combined with the the user of a symbol 0 for zero to
denote a nonexistant number; this marks the birth of modern mathematics. This system was invented in India, probably
during the first millennium before Christ, but was first systematized by the Hindu mathematician and astronomer
Aryabhata I at the tail end of the  fifth century and then transmitted to the West via the Arabs (hence the phrase
"Arabic Numerals"). Before this time, even simple arithmetic was tedious and time-consuming (as when the Romans and
Greeks used the cumbersome "Roman numerals" - sometime still used in the west). And math, of course, is essential
for all science. Without the early invention of zero and place value as well as the use of the a symbol to denote
an unknown quantity in an equation (algebra), also from India, subsequent developments could not have occurred.
There would be no calculus, no newtonian or Galilean science, no computers, and essentially no modern world.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keith Devlin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"What is the most important invention in the past two thousand years?" is one of those questions that
no correct answer - like "What is the best novel / symphony / movie?" - But if I had to make a choice,
it would be the Hindu-Arabic number system, which reached essentially it's present form in the sixth
century. Without it, Galileo would have been unable to begin the quantificational study of nature which we
now call science, and we would not have had calculus, another major invention of the period in question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before of it's linguistic structure, the Hindu-Arabic number system allows humans who have an innate linguistic
fluency but only a very primitive number sense to use their ability with language to handle numbers of virtually
any useful magnitude, with as much precision as required. Today there is scarcely any aspect of life that
does not depend on our ability to handle numbers efficiently and accurately. True, we now use computers to
do much of our number crunching, but without the Hindu-Arabic number system we would not have any computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to it's use in arithmetic and science, the Hindu-Arabic number system is the only genuinely
universal language on earth - apart, perhaps, from the Windows Operating System, which has achieved
the near universal adoption of a conceptually and technologically poor product by the sheer force
of market dominance. By contrast, the Hindu-Arabic number system gained worldwide acceptance because
it is far better designed and much more efficient for human usage than any other number system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/11/26/the-indo-arabic-number-system.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 23:43:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Myth of a Strong Leader</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/the-myth-of-a-strong-leader.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Myth of a Strong Leader" by Archie Brown is from Bill Gates book recommendation. Pause a moment and think about the title. Every now and then you will hear something saying "Strong Leader", you  never hear people saying "we need a weak leader".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book's title is that, the concept of "Strong Leader" is a myth.
According to the book, an effective person works by collaboration, flexibility and never becomes a center point of decision making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gatesnotes.com/Books/The-Myth-of-the-Strong-Leader"&gt;Review link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/the-myth-of-a-strong-leader.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 02:51:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work - Amazon Book Link</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2010/10/09/the-pleasures-and-sorrows-of-work-amazon-book-link.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is editorial book appearing in this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="vt-p" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/037542444X/krondonet-20"&gt;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/037542444X/krondonet-20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It presents a very interesting view on how the perception of Work and Life  has changed over the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alain de Botton on The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work to shine a spotlight on the working world. I wanted to write a book that would open our eyes to the beauty and occasional horror of the working world—and I did this by looking at 10 different industries, a deliberately eclectic range from accountancy to engineering, from biscuit manufacture to logistics. The strangest thing about the world of work is the widespread expectation that our work should make us happy. For thousands of years, work was viewed as something to be done with as rapidly as possible and escaped in the imagination through alcohol or religion. Aristotle was the first of many philosophers to state that no one could be both free and obliged to earn a living. A more optimistic assessment of work had to wait until the eighteenth century and men like Jean-Jacques Rousseau and Benjamin Franklin, who for the first time argued that one's working life could be at the centre of any desire for happiness. It was during this century that our modern ideas about work were formed—at the very same time as our modern ideas about love and marriage took shape.  In the pre-modern age, it was assumed that no one could try to be in love and married: marriage was something one did for purely commercial reasons. Things were going well if you maintained a tepid friendship with your spouse. Meanwhile, love was something you did with your mistress, with pleasure untied to the responsibilities of child-rearing. Yet the new philosophers of love argued that one might actually aim to marry the person one was in love with rather than just have an affair. To this unusual idea was added the even more peculiar notion that one might work both for money and to realise one's dreams, an idea that replaced the previous assumption that the day job took care of the rent and anything more ambitious had to happen in one's spare time.  We are the heirs of these two very ambitious beliefs: that you can be in love and married, and in a job and having a good time. It has become as impossible for us to think that you could be out of work and happy as it had once seemed impossible for Aristotle to think that you could be employed and human. Thus is born The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work. —Alain de Botton&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2010/10/09/the-pleasures-and-sorrows-of-work-amazon-book-link.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2010 15:36:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Agony and the Ecstasy</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2008/12/13/the-agony-and-the-ecstasy.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That night, as he lay sleepless in bed, he thought. &lt;i&gt;"Life has bee good. God did not create me to abandon me. I have loved marble, yes and paint too. I have loved architecture, and poetry too. I have loved my family and my friends. I have loved God the forms of the earth and the heavens, and people too. I have loved life to the full, and now I love death as its natural termination. Il Magnifico would be happy: for me, the forces of destruction never overcame creativity" &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Agony_and_the_Ecstasy_(novel)"&gt;The Agony and the Ecstasy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2008/12/13/the-agony-and-the-ecstasy.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 23:34:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>