<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Senthil Kumaran's thoughts. (Posts about books)</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/categories/books.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 14:37:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Finished Reading: The Meaning Of It All - Richard Feynman</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/04/03/finished-reading-the-meaning-of-it-all-richard-feynman.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/w6ilwgd9niepm8c/meaning_of_it_all.png" class="align-center" src="https://dl.dropbox.com/s/w6ilwgd9niepm8c/meaning_of_it_all.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a short non-technical book consisting of compiled speeches of Richard Feynman. It does not into physics, but
covers a lot of topics like religion, politics, society, ethical questions in science, atom bombs and scientist
motivations. Richard feynman has lot of context to explore all these areas. Plus, his communication style is very
pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually avoid reading general books like this. But I happen to pick this up, and on a day, when I was about to give
some leeway into an astrology (it's not a science) shared by my close ones, having just reading a topic in this book
gave me excellent points to bring my thinking back into track. Contrary to my assumption when starting to read this
book, I found it extremely useful!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2017/04/03/finished-reading-the-meaning-of-it-all-richard-feynman.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 17:29:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Myth of a Strong Leader</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/the-myth-of-a-strong-leader.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Myth of a Strong Leader" by Archie Brown is from Bill Gates book recommendation. Pause a moment and think about the title. Every now and then you will hear something saying "Strong Leader", you  never hear people saying "we need a weak leader".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book's title is that, the concept of "Strong Leader" is a myth.
According to the book, an effective person works by collaboration, flexibility and never becomes a center point of decision making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gatesnotes.com/Books/The-Myth-of-the-Strong-Leader"&gt;Review link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/the-myth-of-a-strong-leader.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 02:51:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work - Amazon Book Link</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2010/10/09/the-pleasures-and-sorrows-of-work-amazon-book-link.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is editorial book appearing in this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="vt-p" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/037542444X/krondonet-20"&gt;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/037542444X/krondonet-20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It presents a very interesting view on how the perception of Work and Life  has changed over the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alain de Botton on The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work to shine a spotlight on the working world. I wanted to write a book that would open our eyes to the beauty and occasional horror of the working world—and I did this by looking at 10 different industries, a deliberately eclectic range from accountancy to engineering, from biscuit manufacture to logistics. The strangest thing about the world of work is the widespread expectation that our work should make us happy. For thousands of years, work was viewed as something to be done with as rapidly as possible and escaped in the imagination through alcohol or religion. Aristotle was the first of many philosophers to state that no one could be both free and obliged to earn a living. A more optimistic assessment of work had to wait until the eighteenth century and men like Jean-Jacques Rousseau and Benjamin Franklin, who for the first time argued that one's working life could be at the centre of any desire for happiness. It was during this century that our modern ideas about work were formed—at the very same time as our modern ideas about love and marriage took shape.  In the pre-modern age, it was assumed that no one could try to be in love and married: marriage was something one did for purely commercial reasons. Things were going well if you maintained a tepid friendship with your spouse. Meanwhile, love was something you did with your mistress, with pleasure untied to the responsibilities of child-rearing. Yet the new philosophers of love argued that one might actually aim to marry the person one was in love with rather than just have an affair. To this unusual idea was added the even more peculiar notion that one might work both for money and to realise one's dreams, an idea that replaced the previous assumption that the day job took care of the rent and anything more ambitious had to happen in one's spare time.  We are the heirs of these two very ambitious beliefs: that you can be in love and married, and in a job and having a good time. It has become as impossible for us to think that you could be out of work and happy as it had once seemed impossible for Aristotle to think that you could be employed and human. Thus is born The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work. —Alain de Botton&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2010/10/09/the-pleasures-and-sorrows-of-work-amazon-book-link.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2010 15:36:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Agony and the Ecstasy</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2008/12/13/the-agony-and-the-ecstasy.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That night, as he lay sleepless in bed, he thought. &lt;i&gt;"Life has bee good. God did not create me to abandon me. I have loved marble, yes and paint too. I have loved architecture, and poetry too. I have loved my family and my friends. I have loved God the forms of the earth and the heavens, and people too. I have loved life to the full, and now I love death as its natural termination. Il Magnifico would be happy: for me, the forces of destruction never overcame creativity" &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Agony_and_the_Ecstasy_(novel)"&gt;The Agony and the Ecstasy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2008/12/13/the-agony-and-the-ecstasy.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 23:34:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Books I could read this year</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2007/12/31/books-i-could-read-this-year.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li&gt; Men who made new physics. &lt;br&gt;

It is story of the physicists who heralded the new era of physics.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Five Dollar Smile. &lt;br&gt;

One of the early writings of Shashi Tharoor, perhaps when he was in college. Stories feature subjects which occupy adolescent minds. Subjects like friendship, love, sex and politics are dealt with in a very comical way.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; How I taught my grandma and other stories. &lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Old man and his god. &lt;br&gt;

Both the books by madam Sudha Murty. Most of the stories upheld values, virtuous nature in human beings, human dignity, many ethical and philanthropic subjects. &lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Its not about Bike. &lt;br&gt;

It is all about strength and courage by the cyclist, marathon guy Lance Armstrong, who defeated cancer to get back to race and win the Tour de France 5 times.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Just do it. &lt;br&gt;

Very practical advice from Sir. Richard Branson. He just did the Virgin empire and encourages everyone to just do what one wants to do. &lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Bridges of Madison County.&lt;br&gt;

Very romantic one. In fact, the best romantic book I have read so far. Writing is very good and it is a subject which could lie on the borderline of love and infidelity, but author has dealt it in a wonderful way that the reader can understand and sometimes agree with the borderline which it portrays.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Guide to Earth, Moon and Space. &lt;br&gt;

Asimov's non-fiction writing. His writing is very lucid and it tries to bring back the questions that a curious child wonders when standing outside and looking at the night sky. Questions like, &lt;i&gt;"What are those shiny things?, Why is it there?, Why is not falling?, Why are so many of them there?, Why is it dark now?, Is sun asleep?, When we travel in a scooter how come moon is also traveling along with us?Can we race ahead of it?"&lt;/i&gt;. Those are just fun and very valid questions. Asimov tries to answer them all as it can be understood by the child who asks those questions. The book is simply too good. I really loved it.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Theory of Everything.&lt;br&gt;

Stephen Hawkings explains science as it evolved from the times of Galileo till the string theory. It is easy to read, and presented in a very concise manner.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Revenge of the Baby Sat.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Calvin and Hobbes 1st book.&lt;br&gt;

Both of them, lovable Calvin and Hobbes adventures.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Asterix series.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt; Asterix the Gaul

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Asterix and the Golden Sickel

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Asterix and the Goths.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Asterix and the Chieftains Shield.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; The Mansions of the Gods.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Asterix and the Soothsayer.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Asterix and Caesar's Gift.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Fantastic Voyage. &lt;br&gt;

Asimov's fiction, which is, in fact is based on the screenplay of a movie by the same name. The book came much earlier than the movie. Three men and a woman, miniature themselves and enter inside the human body,in a miniaturized submarine to do an operation. They will have complete the operation and get out of body within a time limit, otherwise even as their goal fails, everyone stands at a danger of losing something very valuable, the information available with the person they are trying to save at any cost.

Asimov has taken take to write fiction in very logical way. Like the troop experience the "Brownian Motion" as they enter inside the body. &lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Out of my Comfort Zone. &lt;br&gt;

Steve Waugh's Biography. While reading this, I had many fits of laughter, many a moments of amusement and wonder at this simple guy with lot of character. Steve is definitely one of my favorite sports person. He is very plain and direct. And a very bold person too as we can see in his auto-biography. Good lessons on leadership and management is presented in his book.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Krishna and Gopal.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Savitri&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Buddhist Tales&lt;br&gt;

From Amar Chitra Katha series, based on folklore, mythology and ancient Indian stories. They deal the moral values, justice, ethical leadership and administration. &lt;br&gt;

I have more Amar Chitra Katha books to read.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Hound of Baskervilles.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Sign of Four &lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Study in Scarlet &lt;br&gt;

Those were the brilliance of Sir. Arthur Canon Doyle through Sherlock Holmes and Dr. Watson. I read these for the second time as I had completed the sherlock holmes series a long time back.



&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of these books, like "Guide to Earth, Moon and Space", "Theory of Everything", Sherlock Holmes series, I read along with my friend Avinash and we both enjoyed it together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from these, there are few technical books, I could &lt;i&gt;lay my hands upon&lt;i&gt;. Note , technical books are not meant to be read, they are to be studied thoroughly and worked upon a number of times. So, I cannot put them in the read category.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could get chance to work with,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt; Version Control with Subversion by Ben Collins-Sussman,

Brian W. Fitzpatrick, C. Michael Pilato.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Word power made easy by Norman Lewis.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Cryptography and Network Security, by William Stallings.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://aarthimuralidharan.blogspot.com"&gt;My friend&lt;/a&gt; and I had thought at the start of year to compete for the &lt;a href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2007/12/31/www.livejournal.com/community/50bookchallenge"&gt;50bookchallenge&lt;/a&gt;. While that was my list of books, I am glad that we got started and next year, I plan to read at least 50 books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you would like to read any of these books, I would be glad to share it with you. You can also have a peek into my online library at &lt;a href="http://books.google.co.in/books?as_list=BDQiZH8QQiLL-oPzi3N_xARoUPZY8CAHGfBKJvMKvuOm5YfglkA8"&gt;books.google.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year 2008 to all!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2007/12/31/books-i-could-read-this-year.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 05:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Recent Books</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2007/02/22/recent-books.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My friend and I am participating in the &lt;a href="http://community.livejournal.com/50bookchallenge/profile"&gt;50bookchallenge&lt;/a&gt; and I have started enjoying reading one book after the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Men who made new physics, I started reading Shashi Tharoors &lt;a href="http://www.shashitharoor.com/books/five-dollar/fivedollarsmile.htm"&gt;"5 Dollar Smile"&lt;/a&gt;. This is a compilation of a early writings of Sashi Tharoor in his adolescence. So, you might find him attracted towards pretty girls, interest in sex topics and many of things which disturb young adults. His writing style is good and its really funny. He in his college days might be a kind of  leader who must have been along with friends teasing, having fun,understanding junta and yet a leader, Not the all prefect high standards that comes in book definitions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last one act play of a "Life of a Kutta" was amazing, its a set in a period of India Emergency when forced sterilization was done on males. This presents the time from the eyes of a dog who is converted to a man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.shashitharoor.com/books/five-dollar/fivedollarsmilecover.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title "5 Dollar Smile" refers to UN Post card featuring photo of Child from India, which seeks to donate 5 dollars and make him smile. Its a simple story of a boy with a charity. The stories are not conclusive, but many of them are thought provoking and sometimes reflecting with real world incidents as it happens and passes by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next book I read was Sudha Murthy's  "&lt;a href="http://www.hinduonnet.com/thehindu/mp/2004/05/20/stories/2004052000240100.htm"&gt;How I taught my Grandma and Other stories.&lt;/a&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.hinduonnet.com/thehindu/mp/2004/05/20/images/2004052000240101.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very good book stressing on moral values and principles in life. Sudhar Murty has narrated the incidents in her life in a very simple style for others to understand and follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title refers to the story of her youth, when she used to say featured monthly story to her grandma and once in her absence her grandma felt helpless with her inability to read. Her grandma took a resolve to start learning and made young Sudha Mmurty as her guru. This is has very emotional touch at the end which relates to a student respecting her guru.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing imprinted in mind is, she learnt from a charity work of not delaying things when helping people as help at the right time is proper and delay with it is not good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her story about meetings with JRD Tata and APJ Kalaam was very inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>books</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2007/02/22/recent-books.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2007 00:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>