<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Senthil Kumaran (Posts about personal)</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/categories/cat_personal.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 18:42:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Trip to Santa Cruz, Carmel and Big Sur</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/trip-to-santa-cruz-carmel-and-big-sur.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I planned for a family weekend trip to few coastal towns in California. My dad
was visiting us and before he returned back to India, I thought it was a good
idea to tour some nearby places. Plus, it was a welcome relief after all the
work of moving to the new home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As my wife would say, something that I should avoid doing, it was last minute
plan. On wednesday, I went about planning for my leave at office and started
booking hotels. Hotels near tourist spots often get booked during weekends and I
had to pay my price of getting hold of something which was a bit away from
tourist spots, but in a beautiful small town called &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wikiwand.com/en/Salinas,_California"&gt;Salinas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using wikipedia and google maps, I noted down the following places that will be
worth visiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pigeon_Point_Lighthouse"&gt;Pegion Point Light House&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mystery_Spot"&gt;Mystery Spot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Santa_Cruz_Beach_Boardwalk"&gt;Santa Cruz Broad Walk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Piedras Blancas Light Station [cancelled]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Point_Sur_Lighthouse"&gt;Point Sur Light House&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monterey_Bay_Aquarium"&gt;Monterey Aquarium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mission_San_Carlos_Borromeo_de_Carmelo"&gt;Mission San Carlos Borroméo del río Carmelo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bixby_Creek_Bridge"&gt;Bixby Creek Bridge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hearst Castle [cancelled]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/sankat-mochan-hanuman-temple-watsonville"&gt;Mt Madonna Hanuman Temple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could make it most of them and I had to cancel a few because were very far
from the place we stayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have visited Monetery twice earlier, I was enthusiastic to travel to the
peninsula again and take Siddhartha to Aquarium second time in row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santa Cruz beach has free concerts on Friday evenings and  we got a chance to
watch the live performance of of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.yandtrocks.com/"&gt;Y and T&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Bigsur, we could be on time for a 02:00 pm tour of Point Sur light house.
It's trek lasting for 3 hours up to the light house led by a guide, who has a
good narrative on light houses in california, living in early 1900s in the light
house and current preservation efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next day, we visited Mission San Carlos at Carmel, which was one of the earliest
missions established in California by Junipero Sierra. These monuments provide a
window to peek at events back in time. I enjoy watching through it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday, on our way back to home, we made a trip to Hanuman Temple at Mount
Madonna, Watsonville. This is actually a Yoga retreat setup by folks and is
guided by an Indian guru by name Baba Ram Doss. The location of this Hindu
temple was excellent and at atmosphere was serene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was our last spot in the journey. All throughout, we tried different local
foods, and sometim food chains as it was easy choice. We planned a little,
executed mostly on our plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of our &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://goo.gl/photos/fMz7sEm8kT5pJy3t8"&gt;Tour Photos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/trip-to-santa-cruz-carmel-and-big-sur.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 06:07:25 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>