<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Senthil Kumaran's thoughts. (Posts about insights)</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/categories/insights.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:27:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Maharishi Mahesh Yogi died last week.</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2008/02/08/maharishi-mahesh-yogi-passes-away.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maharishi_Mahesh_Yogi"&gt;Maharishi Mahesh Yogi&lt;/a&gt;, was the guru of Transcendental Meditation technique. There are many different meditation techniques in the world. Meditation is a concept for your thoughts, which is similar physical exercise is for body.
&lt;p&gt;Transcendental Meditation is one of them and Maharishi Mahesh Yogi pioneered it. I learned it when I was in 10th  standard,16 years old and practiced it till my first year at job when I was in tech-support department at Dell, 23 years old. I feel, I had started meditation, because I wanted to improve my marks and achieve big things :-) and pursued it for 7 years intermittently, constantly getting confused with many things, without achieving the purpose of marks and big things. During this time, the Meditation activity also took me into religion and other spiritual activities in the related sphere and I got easily influenced by them also. My interests included, Sri Ramakrishna Mutt, Swami Vivekananda, Osho, temples and various different philosophical reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was when doing night-shifts at work that I did not get time for these and because during the day time with whatever time  I got, I wanted to study and prepare for a move to software development that my interests in meditation started to fade away. I think, being in Bangalore than in Madurai (where you have lot of temples and average interest in spiritual things is very high) and away from some friends who had shared my previous interests also led to this change. I was also disgusted with wrong paths which people might follow, if they just pray to god and not do the required work in trying to achieve what they wanted. So many nearby examples and sometimes myself included were in my mind. So, I simply kind of gave it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our interests change at different points in time. Right now, I do &lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/mXsw1QhEnuio4b4DA"&gt;physical exercises&lt;/a&gt; everyday, enjoy it without any aim for marks or achieving big things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When thinking about the subject of meditation sometimes, I feel that it can be equated to exercises for your thoughts and it should not be a heavy subject however and should definitely not be linked with many things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are lots of article on Mahesh Yogi, Beatles involvement and Mahesh Yogi's achievements in field of meditation under the entertainment section of the news today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>insights</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2008/02/08/maharishi-mahesh-yogi-passes-away.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2008 00:06:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>