<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Senthil Kumaran's thoughts. (Posts about movies)</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/categories/movies.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 13:57:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Movie Review: Saving Private Ryan</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/movie-review-saving-private-ryan.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We got the Netflix subscription recently and one of the movies I watched after getting Netflix was "Saving Private
Ryan".  Surprisingly, I had not watched this movie earlier. Every time I watched the opening scene, I had simply given
up and that was enough of the movie for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, that I completely watched it, this movie just my regard for "Steven Speilberg" as the director. I can think of no
other movie that is as brilliant, portraying human emotions, as this one. The war is shown in its brutality. Soldiers
holding on religion as the moment of truth is shown dearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The characters in the movie include Captain Miller (Tom Hanks) who shows extraordinary leadership and Private Jackson
(Barry Pepper), a highly reliable, accurate marksman, who quotes bible, gives himself unto god, as he fights his
enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything about this movie was great.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>movies</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/movie-review-saving-private-ryan.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 17:17:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Movie Review: No Country For Old Men</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/movie-review-no-country-for-old-men.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Rating: 4/5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a decent chance that you must have heard about this movie. I had heard the
name too, had a vague idea from reading synopsis what I would expect.  But I was
totally wrong. After a point, I said to myself, it is no longer good vs. evil story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has a very thin storyline but has an excellent performance
from the villain, gripping scenes that will keep you absorbed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won't the read book, but I enjoyed watching the movie.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>movies</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/movie-review-no-country-for-old-men.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 16:46:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Papanasam</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2015/07/19/papanasam.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Papanasam is the first movie wherein I noticed that Kamal Hassan as a character in the movie didn't make any fun of god. In fact, in one scene wherein he tussles with the inspector at the tea shop, he refers to people as capable of being judged only by "the almighty". That's more philosophical, but in a later scene he mocks a cinema operator as "Nee yeena Karuppu Sattai ya?" (Are you an atheist?)  taking the opposite stance he usually plays on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is same as Drishyam and I didn't mind watching it again in Tamil. What I liked about the whole thing was even an accomplished actor like Kamal agreeing to act ditto and not shying away from a remake. This, in my opinion, is a credit both to the story as well as to the creative artist who wants to do the same project in a different language because the project itself is a brilliant one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>movies</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2015/07/19/papanasam.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 20:21:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Good Will Hunting</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2008/06/12/good-will-hunting.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At last my desktop computer running FC2 was able to play movies from VCD. VLC did the trick and I had to spend considerable time with it to make it play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) vlc vcd:///dev/hdc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) next to scroll bar there was chapter button. Click on that so that it does not finish with the advertisements only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good Will Hunting was an 'okay' movie.  It was trying to be a sentimental, emotional one. But there were lots of loop holes. Well movies as such have lots, but this was a little extra special in terms of mathematical genius janitor who is an autodidactic and considers himself correct all the times. Robin Williams plays the psychologist part and tries to help him find his way. Which you can expect in a movie, would be to get back to his heroine with whom he had a break-up. Thats following his heart. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked the slangs used, the boston country side and bars potrayed and the joke the heroine shares in bar with friends.  :-)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>movies</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2008/06/12/good-will-hunting.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 09:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>