<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Senthil Kumaran (Posts about personality)</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.xtoinfinity.com/categories/personality.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:32:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Two things that has been etched in my mind about Sachin</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2012/12/24/two-things-that-i-been-etched-in-my-mind-about-sachin.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sachin's score 138 against Pakistan in a late nighties tour. He was fighting a severe back ache and then hitting the pakistan bowlers all over the ground. As soon as he got out, India fell short of 17 runs from victory. To me, victory does not count anything, but this attempt of a person carrying the team, overcoming personal physical pain and going for it was an enormous gesture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sachin returned to his work, i.e. playing cricket and scoring a century against Kenya in a world cup, one day after his father died says millions about work ethic, concentration and love for something. His family appreciated him for that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>india</category><category>personality</category><category>sachin</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2012/12/24/two-things-that-i-been-etched-in-my-mind-about-sachin.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2012 08:21:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Shavarsh Karapetyan</title><link>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2012/10/12/shavarsh-karapetyan.html</link><dc:creator>Senthil Kumaran</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shavarsh_Karapetyan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Karapetyan had just completed his usual distance of 20 km (12 mi) when he heard the sound of the crash and saw the sinking trolleybus which had gone out of control and fallen from the dam wall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trolleybus lay at the bottom of the reservoir some 25 metres (80 ft) offshore at a depth of 10 metres (33 ft). Karapetyan swam to it and, despite conditions of almost zero visibility, due to the silt rising from the bottom, broke the back window with his legs. The trolleybus was crowded, it carried 92 passengers and Karapetyan knew he had little time, spending some 30 to 35 seconds for each person he saved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Karapetyan managed to rescue 20 people (he picked up more, but only 20 survived), but this ended his sports career: the combined effect of cold water and the multiple wounds he received (scratched by glass), left him unconscious for 45 days. Subsequent sepsis, due to the presence of raw sewage in the lake water, and lung complications prevented him from continuing his sports career.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On February 19th, 1985, Shavarsh just happened to be near a burning building, that had people trapped inside. He rushed in and started pulling people out without a second thought. Once again, he was badly hurt (severe burns) and spent a long time in the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He later moved to Moscow and founded a shoe company called “Second Breath”. Karapetyan was later awarded a UNESCO “Fair Player” medal for his heroism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a title="Main belt" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Main_belt"&gt;main belt&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="Asteroid" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asteroid"&gt;asteroid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="3027 Shavarsh" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/3027_Shavarsh"&gt;3027 Shavarsh&lt;/a&gt;, discovered by &lt;a title="Nikolai Chernykh" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nikolai_Chernykh"&gt;Nikolai Chernykh&lt;/a&gt;, was named after him (approved by the &lt;a title="Minor Planet Center" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minor_Planet_Center"&gt;MPC&lt;/a&gt; in September 1986).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>personality</category><guid>http://www.xtoinfinity.com/posts/2012/10/12/shavarsh-karapetyan.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 19:51:32 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>